[SOUND]
So
if you want to try any of these
scalable vector graphics examples,
you can go to wthreeschools.com and
there's an SVG tutorial section there.
And it gives you a window here
where you can type in SVG code.
For example, here and
it's output comes here.
So for example, this one's
setting up a drawing canvas, and
it's specified in pixels.
So the canvas coordinates are going to
be equal to the display coordinates,
going from 00 here, to 100, 100 here,
it's drawing a circle centered.
If, 50/50 in the middle of radius 40.
If I can that to a 50 and
then see the results you can see that
it's extending out to the boundary
of the drawing canvas.
We can use this to interactively
change different attributes
of an SVG drawing and
see the results being plotted.
And that way you can experiment with
different methods for setting up
coordinate systems or drawing various
shapes in scalable vector graphics.
[MUSIC]