In some cases, we'll need to use
three-dimensional computer graphics for
data visualization.
To understand how three-dimensional
computer graphics works,
you have to understand how light leaves
a light source, reflects off of an object,
and then reaches your eye,
so it can be perceived.
So now we'll discuss three-dimensional
graphics for visualization.
So what will we learn?
We'll learn about the real-world ways
that light leaves a light source,
and reaches our eye.
We'll learn the physics of why is
the sky blue, why is the sun yellow,
why is grass green?
And in general, how does three-dimensional
graphic simulate these physical processes?
And so here is a typical scene of the real
world, and how we would perceive that?
We have a light source,
an object reflecting light, and a sensor,
which is our eye.
And light leaves,
in this case, the sun and
it's the slightest powerful across the
spectrum, and so it's essentially white.
But then that light goes to the sky, and
the sky scatters the light differently
based on which region of
the spectrum it's dealing with.
So light at the red wavelengths
will get scattered less, and
light at the blue wavelengths will get
scattered more, so that light gets
scattered to other locations in the sky,
which makes the sky blue.
And which makes the sun appear yellow,
because that light's hitting
all the way through.
That yellow sunlight hits a tree,
or grass, or any other biome.
And certain wavelengths of that light are
getting absorbed by chlorophyll molecules,
and turned into hotosynthate,
which feeds the tree.
And so the chlorophyll is absorbing light,
mostly in the blue regions, in the blue
wavelengths, and in the red wavelengths,
and reflecting light, not absorbing
the light, in the green wavelengths.
So the light reflected off
of a tree is mostly green.
And so then, it hits it in the eye,
reaches our sensor in our eye,
so that we can perceive it.
And there it gets sensed by,
essentially, cones, the colors,
the wavelengths of light,
stimulate three different kinds of cones,
a mostly red cone, a mostly green cone,
and a mostly blue cone.
And these send three different
responses to our perceptual system.
And so you may have a complex wavelength
of light indicating its color.
But at some point,
when the eye perceives that,
that gets turned into three numbers
instead of a bunch of numbers, and
so we get this tristimulus
theory of light perception.
And that's why we display
things using red, green,
blue colors in pixels on graphics displays
to directly stimulate the red cones,
the green cones, and the blue cones.
So we can simulate this process, and
we can look, for example, at a camera.
And a modern camera, in this case,
a pin-hole camera that has a very small
aperture, is getting light reflected
off of an object, in this case,
this blue bunny rabbit,
that goes through a focal point.
And it gets projected onto an image plane
that would be sensed then in modern
cameras by a CCD array.
We can take that image plane, and we can
just bring that in front of the camera,
and we get the exact same
image that's not inverted.
It's just placed in front.
And you can think of this
as being a window, and
you're looking through a window out
into the world, and seeing a blue bunny.
You could imagine where that blue bunny
would be on the window that you see there.
And that's the exact same image inverted
that you would get on the film plane,
because of the geometry
of this camera system.
Well, we can remove the camera system, and
we can put an eye right at that focal
point, and this gives us this image plane.
And so basically when we're looking out
into a three-dimensional scene, what we're
seeing is the same thing that would be
projected onto a two-dimensional window to
the world through those some projectors
just a certain fixed distance away.
And that's the way we can simulate
with a two-dimensional image
what the eye would see in
a three-dimensional world.
And in computer graphics, as we discussed
before with two-dimensional graphics,
we're going to simulate shapes
using primitives, in this case,
vector primitives.
Except these are now three-dimensional
vector primitives, and
so we have triangles.
And the triangles are specified
by three vertices.
And those three vertices have
edges between them and a region,
we'll call a polygonal face.
And you can create a mesh of these
triangles to define a three-dimensional
object, in this case, a bunny rabbit.
And those triangles are then
projected by what's called
a three-dimensional graphics pipeline
onto a two-dimensional image plane.
And then the polygons
on that two-dimensional
image plane are then
discretized into pixels.
This is a rasterization process and,
in fact, the same rasterization process we
were discussing in two-dimensional
graphics, where regions and
edges are discretized into pixels, instead
of straight lines and continuous regions.
And so the way 3D graphics works is for
each one of these triangles,
each one of these primitives, we're
going to figure out its illumination by
simulating the light coming from
a light source reflecting off of it.
And then we're going to
project that triangle and
its lumination onto this image plane.
And then we're going to rasterize that
triangle by filling its region in with
pixels.
And that's what gets displayed
on the pixel display.
And so we can speak of these
processes as vertex processing.
This is also called transform and
lighting,
where we're taking vertices of triangles,
and projecting them on to an image plane.
Rasterization, taking those
two-dimensional triangles, and
converting them into pixels.
And then pixel processing which
takes those pixel regions,
and figures out what color
should be on their interior.
We also will need to view
three-dimensional scenes.
We need to figure out where
is the eye in the scene.
And so we'll set up things
like world coordinate systems.
And this eye and
this teapot example will be
located at positions in three-dimensional
coordinates in the same way that
primitives were located in two-dimensional
coordinates in the previous example.
So we use this world coordinate system,
and its origin is off some place, and
we can describe everything relative
to this coordinate system.
And we will specify a view, basically,
where are we and what are we looking at?
Our eye point will be located at a certain
set of coordinates in world coordinates.
And will be looking at a point also
specified as a set of coordinates in world
coordinates, three coordinates, x, y, z.
And then that view is going to be
transformed into a new coordinate system
that looks very similar to our
canvas coordinate system, so
that we have an x axis and a y axis.
And, in this case,
we're extending from (-1,-1) to (1,1).
And these coordinates are the coordinates
of the window we were looking through
that forms the image plane.
And another thing we want to do is
to create a sense of perspective, so
that things farther away appear smaller,
and things closer to us appear larger.
In computer graphics, we do that by
processing the primitives themselves.
We actually make the things that
are farther away smaller, and
the things that are closer to us larger.
So this may look correct for a perspective
scene of a teapot on a table, but
if I look at it from the side view, what
I've actually done is made the front of
the table larger, and
the back of the table is smaller.
So that when it gets projected
onto my 2-D image plane,
I get correct proportions for
a perspective rendering.
And from this point,
we've processed our primitives, and
we would then rasterize them and fill them
in, in the same fashions that we did for
two-dimensional graphics examples.
So we learned that
three-dimensional graphics
displays objects that are made
out of triangle meshes.
And that these triangle meshes
are projected onto an image plane.
And we specify how that
projection happens with a view.
We specify that view with an eye point, a
viewing direction, and in an up direction.
And then we use perspective
to do that projection,
so that things closer to us appear
larger than things farther away.
Also, the way the computer processes
three-dimensional computer graphics is
with a pipeline consisting of vertex
processing, then rasterization, and
then pixel processing.
[MUSIC]
[SOUND]