When we're using
three-dimensional graphics for
data visualization, often we don't want
something that looks like a photograph.
We want something that looks
more like an illustration.
In this case, we want to use something
called non-photorealistic rendering.
If we can photograph or
render with computer graphics everything,
then why do we need things
like illustrations?
And the answer is is that
illustrations can more clearly depict
a three-dimensional configuration
than a photograph can.
And so then the question is how can we use
three-dimensional computer graphics to
render an illustration?
So, a good example of this form
of non-photorealistic rendering
is Gray's Anatomy.
And here's an illustration of
the human heart from Gray's Anatomy,
and it's not a photograph.
A photograph would be gory and
covered with blood, and
it would be hard to see all
of these configurations.
But with an illustration, the artist has
much more control over the lighting, and
the texturing, and
the cutaways in order to more clearly
denote the structures of the heart.
What we'd like to do is be able to do
the same thing with data visualization.
So, for example, if I have a simple
model of a pig, I could render it using
photorealistic illumination and occlusion
and fills to get this shape here.
But I could also use non-photorealistic
techniques to get a more cartoony
version of this pig that conveys
much the same information.
And you'll notice that this pig has
outline strokes and it has fills.
And so the outline strokes
are created from contours.
And from a three-dimensional scene,
the way we get those
contours is by tracing them.
They create things like silhouette curves,
the border between the shape and
the background.
And sometimes this boundary
will cover itself,
and other contours of the shading.
And so sometimes these contours will
trace behind other surfaces, and
so we still need to respect occlusion.
So we have to trim away portions of the
contour that are hidden by other regions.
But that leaves us with a set
of outlines and a set of regions
that we can then render using some
of our vector graphics techniques
instead of some of our three-dimensional
photorealistic techniques.
So, when we fill in the surfaces we may
not want to use photorealistic lighting.
So, this top line shows a bunch of spheres
rendered with photorealistic lighting.
And you can see that, in each case,
we have a diffuse color illumination and
then a white specular highlight.
So we're getting diffuse illumination and
specular illumination.
The light source is to the up and
right of the object.
And yet we don't see any information
in the dark side of the moon here,
the dark side of the sphere.
That's because this is shadowed
because of photorealistic lighting.
You're not going to see any
information in the shadows.
You can still see the color of the object
because there's enough ambient light
bouncing around to get the color.
But you don't see any
orientation information,
this very well could be
a disk instead of a sphere.
We know it's a sphere because
of the illuminated side.
And so we can create better depictions,
better illumination of the sphere
using non-photorealistic illumination.
In this case, replacing
the diffuse illumination here with
a non-photorealistic diffuse illumination
that we get by taking the color map.
In this case, going from red to black,
and then mixing it with
a cool-to-warm, in this case,
blue to yellow color map.
And that creates a gradation that goes
from a cool form of red, kind of a bluer
shade of red, all the way to a warmer
shade of red, kind of an orange.
So, we're going from
a violet to an orange.
And then we can apply that to
the entire sphere based on
the orientation of the surface and
the light source.
And then we get more information on the
shadowed side of the object in addition to
the illuminated side of the object.
And these shapes look even more spherical
than they do in the physical case.
So when we're displaying three-dimensional
shapes, in this case, skeletal shapes.
With photorealistic illumination you're
not seeing anything in the dark sides of
these objects because of the nature
of shadows and illumination.
But when we apply non-photorealistic
illumination, we can see these contours.
These divots in the bone that are revealed
by this non-photorealistic shading
that are also hidden in
photorealistic shading.
In both cases,
we've also added the contour to better
indicate the outlines of these shapes.
Here's another example.
This is a photorealistic
rendering of a part, and
this is a non-photorealistic
rendering of a part.
You're missing all of the shape
information of the orientation
of the surface on the shadowed side.
And we gain that with our
non-photorealistic shading.
And also the contours help
us see the configuration and
the definite occlusion of
the individual pieces.
So whereas photorealistic rendering
focuses on the physics of light,
non-photorealistic rendering focuses
on the psychology of perception.
It emphasizes other parts of the image,
for example, the outlines,
the visual contours of the object.
And it uses non-photorealistic shading
to better communicate shape that would
otherwise take very complex lighting.
[MUSIC]