We will discuss
Mining Spatial Colocation Patterns.
What is spatial colocation pattern?
Usually, a group of
spatial features of events
can be frequently colocated
in the same region.
For example,
West Nile Virus may often occur in
the regions with poor mosquito control and
the presence of birds.
So if we can find such patterns,
we may have better way to
control the spread of the virus.
Let's look at the example on the right.
So we have A, B, C,
D as four types of objects.
You can think A could be West Nile Virus,
spread in region.
B could be some mosquito region.
Or C could be in some cities, D could
be the presence of birds, something.
Then we use the address,
means they are colocated.
For example, 3, 6, 17 are co-located,
we used edge to link them together.
And a 4, 7, 10,
16 are co-located together.
We use the edge, linking them together.
Okay, like 2, 9 could be collocated,
but on the other hand a 2,
14, 18, 11, and 15,
these are collocated regions, okay?
Then we may be able to find rowset.
The rule set is this, okay?
If we want to find A, B,
C, D, how many things are,
how many objects are colocated
together as A, B, C, D for types.
When I be able to find four,
seven, 10, 16 are colocated.
And 2, 11, 14, 15 are co-located or
8, 11, 14, 15 are co-located.
That means A, B, C, D we may find two,
actually three instances
they are co-located.
That's they are all set.
On the other hand, A,
B may be a little more.
For example, 5,13 is co-located, 7,
10 is co-located, so
we may find more instances.
Then we may get a colocation
rule like this.
If pattern A is colocating,
whether pattern B may also colocating.
We may find this conditional
probability of the colocation patterns.
That means if we want to find AB may
imply CD, that means if AB are colocated,
likely CD will be colocated
with certain probability.
Then, we need to compute the pattern A,
at what condition,
in how many cases, when A is there,
and AB is also there.
That means Actually AB,
the cases is usually is the case.
You can find A and
in the row AB set, rowset.
Okay, essentially what we need to
calculate is A, B, C, D is a rowset.
You are probably going to see there
are three such cases A, B, C, D together.
But there are four cases A,B together.
So the condition, if you find the A,
B then you find the C, D, colocated.
The condition equals 3 over 4 is 75%.
The conditional probability for
this rule is 75%.
Then the interesting thing is,
can we find such colocation patterns and
rules automatically and efficiently?
Okay.
So let's see how we can derive
an efficient algorithm to find them.
To find efficient algorithms,
we first introduce another concept
called participation ratio.
That means that the feature f is
participating in this pattern c.
What's the probability?
Okay.
So for example A participating in A,
B, C, D, you're broken in C.
A is the red one.
We have one, two, three, four, five.
Five cases you'll find A.
But every time we find A We can find a,
b, c, d.
There are only two such cases like 7 and
14.
That's why we get a 2 over 5
is the participation ratio.
Similarly, if you want to
find D participating in A,
B, C, D, d It actually is the blue circle.
You can see there are only
two blue circles, but
both of them are completely partitioned,
participating in this ABCD pattern.
This simply says you get cases
two over two is 100 percent.
Then we may derive a interesting property
called monotonicity property
of participation ratio, okay?
That means suppose we have c and
c prime as two core location patterns.
But c prime is a subset of c.
Then for every feature f, if feature
is participating in C prime, okay?
Then the probability will be higher
than participating in a superset.
This is quite easily,
can be an either and or
[INAUDIBLE] because you can think about
this, if A participating in A, B then
the chance is higher than
A participating into, in A, B, C, D.
Because every time when A, B occurs.
ABCD also will be.
When A, B, C D occurs,
a, b will also be there.
That's why when f participating in c for
sure the probability or
the participation ratio will be
higher then participating supersect.
So based on the monotonicity,
we can work out an Apriori-like algorithm
to efficient mine colocation patterns.
Let's give such an example.
Suppose minimum feature
support is riveting a sigma,
and a minimum participation
ratio is rewritten as roe.
Then we start from a set
of single feature patterns.
If they are frequent, that means if
their support is no less than sigma.
Okay.
Then, we can keep using upper array
like a principle to find their pairs.
That mean from the single feature pattern
try to find two feature patterns,
three feature patterns grow up to size k.
Anytime we can stop if
the pattern is frequent to anyone
Because once it's not frequent,
it's super patterned will not be frequent.
This is simply based on
the Apriori principle.
Then based on these participation in
ratio monotonicy we will be able to find
all the super patterns of a single
feature or the multiple features.
Suppose we got a feature Is p,
we want to find it's super feature,
okay nor super-pattern.
And we know we can get a little
bigger super-pattern to see
whether it's greater in row.
Anytime if it's not greater in row,
it's super-pattern would not need to be
examined because they cannot
be bigger than row anymore.
So based on these Apriori principle, we
can easily work out efficient algorithms.
So that's the trick or
that's the interestingness if we
can find a monotonicity pattern,
we will be able to work out, Apriori-like
efficient processing algorithms.