In this unit,
we're going to study Mining and
Aggregating Patterns over
Multiple Trajectories.
When we study spatial and
temporal patterns, an important
pattern is trajectory pattern.
That means you look at the points,
the objects,
the moving along the spatial map,
along with time.
So we call these the trajectories.
What we want to find
are trajectory patterns.
One interesting trajectory
pattern mining method
called partition-based
trajectory pattern mining.
They are mining T-patterns,
T means trajectory.
This is a work done by a group
of Italian researchers.
They published in KDD 2007 called
Trajectory Pattern Mining.
Their mining method essentially
is a really good study like busy
traffic in the city.
You can think a city
can't be partitioned into
equal width grids to obtain
regions of interest.
For example,
one grid may represent the museum,
the other grid may represent
the railway or campus.
Then when you study the busy traffic,
they go along the route.
You will be able to find either
what hours or how much time
you will find a very busy traffic and how
long it may take to reach the other side.
So, what we can do is we
can transform each input's
trajectory into a time
annotated symbolic sequence.
For example, you may transform one
location is a railway station.
Another location is Castle Square.
The third location could be museum.
And based on a time, you may say from
the railway station, it takes about 15
minutes to reach Castle Square and takes
2 hours and 15 minutes to reach museum.
And we can use a constraint-based
sequential pattern mining because
each grid is matched
into a symbolic sequence.
So the finer you can use
the symbolic sequence to represent
the whole trajectory and
try to find trajectory pattern is trying
to use constraint-based
sequential pattern mining.
The constraints can be
the range of time delay.
Then, the constraint-based
sequential pattern mining
results can be mapped onto the map
to show how much time it may take
from one location going
to the other location.
That kind of matching T-pattern
will be something like (x0,
y0) after alpha time delay,
you will reach (x1, y1) points.
This will get into explicit
representation of the pattern.
Then another interesting group of studies
are detecting moving object clusters.
That means, you may think trucks.
You may think animals.
They are moving together,
you may want to find their moving
object clusters in this sense.
The first one, definition is flock.
Both flock and
a convoy require k consecutive time
stamp in order to find patterns.
The flock essentially is they require
at least m entities are within
the circular region of radius r, and they
are moving together in the same direction.
Then we call these the flock pattern.
But a flock pattern is a little too
rigid in the sense they require
at least m entities moving in
k consecutive time stamps.
And it's within their movement are within
the circular region of radius r,
they are relative distances.
And sometimes this radius r is too rigid.
The convoy definition is using
density-based clustering.
They don't have to be within radius r.
They can be tighter, or
they can be a little looser.
As long as they form
a density-based clustering,
you'll be able to find those m entities,
and in the k consecutive
time stamps, they move together,
you can think they are convoy patterns.
However, such movement
constraints are still very rigid
in the sense both require
k consecutive time stamps.
We may think like animal
movements as certain time stamp,
the animal may not be so
closely clustered together.
They may spread around to graze or
to do other things.
In that sense, we may relax
this k consecutive time stamps
to allow at certain time stamps,
they probably are quite far apart.
But on the other time stamps,
you will be able to find they
are very closely moving together.
In that sense,
we define such pattern as swarm.
Swarm means the moving objects may
not need to be close together,
all the consecutive time stamps.
Of course, to find such movement pattern,
it will be more
costly than finding flocks and convoys
because the pattern is more relaxed.
Some efficient algorithm has been
developed to mine such pattern.
The paper was published in VLDB 2010.
Now we look at another trajectory pattern
is during clustering try to find them.
We call trajectory clustering.
This could be useful in, for example,
try to find land,
try to forecast a hurricane landfall.
If you overlay many years
of hurricane together,
you may find they may
form very close clusters.
However, if you try to take the whole
hurricane paths as inseparable,
you will not be able to find
such patterns, just because at
certain points of time,
these hurricanes may already nicely.
But at other time,
they may become more spreading
because they were influenced
by different flow of the air.
So try to find such patterns.
We will propose a partitioning and
a grouping approach.
Partitioning means you will first
chop these trajectories, for
each trajectory, you will chop them
into a sequence of segments, okay?
Then after chopping these into sequence
of segments, you will be able to find for
certain fragments,
they are moving in the same direction.
They may form nice patterns.
You can group them together
as trajectory clusters.
Then how we can nicely find such patterns?
For partitioning, you can use minimum
description lens principle called MDL.
The MDL, the general philosophy is,
you try to use minimum number of points,
but
maximally reflect the real
trajectory paths.
That means instead of thinking you
use many, many small fragments,
which are too costly,
you try to use less of them.
But you don't want to use too few,
because you will distort the picture.
You will try to maximally approximate
the real trajectory pass.
In that sense you may say I use
minimum description length principle
when the trajectory started
turning in the sharper angle,
I would try to say these
should be separate points.
Then you may find smaller
number of fragments, but
maximum preserve the shape
of the trajectory.
So this is interesting algorithm
published in SIGMOD 2007 called
Trajectory Clustering:
A Partition-and-Group Framework.
[MUSIC]
[SOUND]