Now, we study another
interesting movement pattern
called Mining Semantics-Rich
Movement Patterns.
We'll first see what is
Frequent Movement Pattern?
Frequent Movement Pattern is
a movement sequence, frequently appears
in the input trajectory database, but
we care more on the semantics here.
For example,
from home to Starbucks to office.
So maybe people, the home maybe different
or office maybe different location,
but this pattern maybe interesting,
even we can consider the home and
office could be just the same semantic
units in different locations.
So comparing to
Frequent Movement Pattern versus
Frequent Sequential Pattern, we can say,
they both are at finding frequent
subsequences from input sequence database.
However, for
mining frequent movement patterns,
we would like to think of similar
places may need to be grouped together
collectively to form frequent subsequences
from the semantic point of view.
Now, we look at
Mining Semantics-Rich Movement Patterns.
The semantics-rich patterns means in
addition to know how people move from
one region to another, we want to also
understand the functions of the regions.
That means we want them see people
moving from office to restaurant or
from home to gym.
So, we promote a two-step
top-down mining approach.
The first step is try to find
a set of a coarse patterns that
reflects people semantic
level transitions.
That means as long as a reaching
carry the similar semantic functions,
we may one to consider they
are the same function or same entity.
Then in the step two,
we split each coarse pattern into several
fine-grained ones by grouping
similar movement snippets together.
This time, we'll consider spatial,
temporal, besides the semantics.
We're going to consider spatial and
temporal features more seriously.
A recent study published in
VLDB 2014 called Splitter,
Mining Fine-Grained Sequential Patterns in
Semantic Trajectories is an interesting
study in this direction.
[MUSIC]