[MUSIC]
In this session,
we're going to introduce cosine
similarity as approximate
measure between two vectors,
how we look at the cosine similarity
between two vectors, how they are defined.
So we can take a text document as example.
A text document can be
represented by a bag of words or
more precise a bag of terms.
Each document can be
represented as a long vector,
each attribute recording
the frequency of a particular term.
The term can be a word or
it can be a phrase.
5 means the term team, actually occurring
in Document 1, five times, okay.
So, we want to compare the similarity
between Document 1 and Document 2.
So how similar they are?
We could use cosine similarity to do that.
Other vector objects like gene
features in micro-arrays can be
represented in the similar
way as a long vector, 'kay.
For information retrieval,
biological taxonomy,
gene feature mapping,
like a micro-array analysis,
these are good applications to compare
similarity between two vectors.
The cosine measure is defined as follows.
For example,
we can consider the term-frequency
vector to look at their similarity.
They are defined by dot
product of these two
vectors divided by
the product of their lengths.
So we look at the, the cosine similarity
definition, and take as an example.
Suppose d sub 1 and
d sub 2 are the vectors of
these two documents, okay,
then we can calculate
their vectors dot product as follows,
'kay.
Then we can calculate the length
of each one of d sub 1's lengths,
calculate using this formula, okay.
D sub 2's two lengths eh,
can be calculated also using the square
root of sum of their product.
Then the cosine similarity can be
calculated using the formula given above.
We can see their cosine
similarity is 0.94,
simply says these two
documents are quite similar.
[MUSIC]