[SOUND].
In this session, we are going to discuss
correlation measures between two
variables, especially we will introduce
covariance and a correlation coefficient.
Before we introduce covariance
between two variables,
we will first examine, or
review the variance for single variable.
What is variance?
I think you all know what is average.
For example the average salary
of employees in a company.
The average also core mean mathematically,
as mu.
So mu is actually the expected value of X,
however, if we just use mean,
we may not be sufficiently
represent the trend or
the spread of the value in the variable X.
Okay.
For example, we may not only like to
know the average salary in a company,
but we also like to know
how this value spreads.
That means whether they are very
close to the middle, to the mean or
they are widespread.
They have many very high salaries and
many very low salaries.
In that case,
we introduce the concept of variance.
Which actually,
is to measure how much the value of X
deviate from the mean, or
the expected value of X.
Essentially we'll use sigma square
to wrap in the variance of X.
Sigma is called a standard deviation.
Variance of X actually is
expected value of X deviates
from the mean if we take
the square simply says,
no matter if it's positive or negative,
we all change them into positive.
Then if X is a discrete variable, okay,
then the formula is written like this.
It simply says we use
some of this function.
This function is actually X deviate
from the meal, from the mean value.
Take the square times X density function.
If X is a continuous variable,
so we will take integral,
where the range is from
minus infinity to infinity.
To that stand we see
variance is the expected
value of the square
deviation from the mean.
For this formula,
we can also do a little transformation.
For example, we can transform for
the expect value of X square
deviation from the mean.
We can write down it's the expected
value of X square minus means square.
This transformation actually has
been introduced in many textbooks.
It's quite simple when I
continue to introduce here.
In many cases, if we write in this form,
it may lead to more efficient computation,
especially when you want to
do incremental computation.
If we take a sample, then the sample
variance is actually the average
square deviation of the data value
xi from the sample mean mu hat.
So the sample variance is
written as sigma hat square.
So we often use this formula, I'll use
a similar transform formula to compute it.
Now we introduce a covariance for
two variables.
Once we get two variables, X1 and X2,
we want to see how these two variable,
they change together,
whether they're going up together or
going down together Which would
be the positive covariance.
Let's look at the definition.
The definition, actually, original
definition is X1 minus mu 1 square.
Now we see, actually these two
variable we want to see X1,
the difference from it's mean value of X1.
X2 the difference from X2's mean value,
or expected value.
And then we look at
their expectation okay.
Mathematically we also can
transform this into this form.
If we get a sample covariance, we look at
the sample covariance between X1 and X2.
So the sample covariance is calculated by
their difference from the sample mean.
So that's also popular to use.
Actually, the sample covariance
can be considered as
a generalization of sample variance.
For example, originally we'll want
to look at the two variables X1 and
the X2, their covariance.
But if we think this 2, X1 and
X2, we replace it by X1.
That means we just look at the two
variable X1, X1, what is their covariance?
Then we can represent these two by one.
Then in that case this sample covariance
of formula., we'll look at this formula,
we change the variable from i2 to i1 and
mu2 to mu1 hat.
So then we'll derive this formula, and
this formula essentially is sigma1 hat,
it's square.
So we probably can easily see,
the sample variance is just a special
case of sample covariance when
the two variables are just the same.
When the covariance
value is greater than 0,
we say it is a positive covariance.
If it's this value is less than
0 it is negative covariance.
If these two variables are independent,
then their covariance is 0.
However, the converse is not true.
That means not when the covariance is 0,
then that mean X1 and
X2 are always independent.
Only under certain additional assumptions,
for example,
if the data follows multivariate
normal distributions.
In that case the covariance
of 0 implies independence.
Now we will look at a concrete example.
Suppose we have two stocks, X1 and X2.
They have the following values in one
week, like these five pairs of values.
Then the question is, whether the stock
effected by the same industry trends,
term is,
whether their price will rise or
fall together.
Then we calculate their covariance.
We were be able to know whether they
are possibly correlate on that one.
So if we look at a covariance
formula especially,
we use more simplified
computation formula.
Then we can carry the expect value
of X1 which is the mean value of X1.
Expect value of X2,
which is the mean value of X2,
then we look at their covarience
actually is, we use this formula.
We look at their product,
their dot product,
then divide by sum of them,
divide by the number of variable pairs.
Then we minus, this is expected value
of X1 and expected value of X2.
Then we get the finer value is 4.
That is, the covariance is greater than 0,
that means X1 and X2,
they rise or fall together.
Then if want to normalize them,
we will introduce correlation coefficient.
That means for two numerical variables,
we want to study their correlation which
essentially is the standard covariance.
That mean we want o normalize the
covariance value where it is the standard
deviation of each variable.
So it is defined as correlation
coefficient as the covariance
divided by the product of
their standards deviation.
Or you can say, the covariance is
divided by the product of variance,
get their square root.
So, if we look at sample correlation for
2 attributes X1 and
X2, then essentially we get a row 1,
2 hat is equal to the sigma 1,
1's hat is essentially
their sample covariance
divided by the sample standard deviation.
In a concrete formula we
can write in this way.
Then, if this correlation
coefficient is greater than 0,
that means A and
B are positively correlated.
That means X1's values increase as X2's.
The higher value greater than 0,
the stronger correlation.
If rho 1, 2 equals 0,
that implies they are independent
under the same assumption as
discussed in the co-variance.
If they are less than 0,
they are negatively correlated.
Then we can look at
the a set of variables.
We can see for example, for
2 variables when they're
perfectly negative correlated,
they line up like this,
their correlation coefficient is -1.
Then if they become not so
perfectly negative correlated,
you will see their trend.
When this value is 0, that's,
you could not see anything
like a positive correlated or
negative correlated.
But when you gradually grow
these correlation coefficient,
you will see their value become more and
more correlated.
When they are perfect correlated,
then their correlation coefficient is 1.
That simply says the correlation
coefficient value range is from -1 to 1.
Okay.
Then if we draw this in the scatter plot,
we'll see the set of points,
their correlation coefficient
changes from -1 to 1 in this shape.
In many cases,
we may want to write for 2 variables,
we may want to write their variance and
the correlation information into
the 2 by 2 covariance matrix form.
For example, you may say the variable
1 is self correlation there,
essentially is their variance Is this 1.
And for their coverence between 1 and
2 is defined here between 2 and
1 is defined here and
then that's variable 2's variance.
So this is a typical 2
by 2 covariance matrix.
In general if we have t,
d numerical attributes,
that means suppose we find a data
sets it has [INAUDIBLE] rows and
d columns that means we really
have d numerical attributes.
Then their covariance matrix
essentially written in this form.
We can see this is the variance
of variable 1, this is variable
of the second dimentions and
this is the variance of the d dimentions.
And the covariance for
each one would be lining up like this.
And we give a few interesting
additional reading.
These are the several books,
they contain interesting chapters
discussing the different measures.
Thank you.
[MUSIC]