[MUSIC]
We first introduce some basic
concepts of clustering validation.
We know clustering is unsupervised method,
in the sense we do not have
any expert to judge whether
this clustering is good or
what should be clustered.
So it is important to
evaluate clustering quality.
That means evaluating
the goodness of the clustering.
Also we want evaluate
clustering stability.
That means to understand the sensitivity
of the clustering results to various
algorithm parameters, for
example, the number of clusters.
That means, what number of clusters is
really good based on our evaluation.
The third one is clustering tendency.
That means whether it's
suitable to do clustering.
That means whether the data has
inherent to grouping structure,
then we should, for
some kind of clustering, to discover it.
[MUSIC]