[SOUND] Now we get into
clustering evaluation,
measuring clustering quality.
Measuring clustering quality is an
important issue just because clustering is
unsupervised measure.
We want to evaluate the goodness
of clustering results
by either some internal or
external measures.
Unfortunately there's no commonly
recognized best suitable measure
in practice.
But there are three categories of
measures we call external measures,
internal measures and relative measures.
For external measures,
we can consider they are supervised,
employ criteria not inherent
to the datasets itself.
That means we may have some prior or
expert knowledge.
For example, some ground truth.
Then we can comparing the clustering
results against the prior or
expert specified knowledge,
using certain clustering quality measure.
Then the second kinds of measure
are called internal measure,
which is unsupervised.
That means the criteria
derived from the data itself.
In that case, we will evaluate the
goodness of clustering by considering how
well the clusters are separated and
how compact the clusters are.
For example,
we can use silhouette coefficient.
The third one is a relative measure.
That means we can directly compare
different class rings using
those obtained via different parameter
setting for the same algorithm.
For example, For the same algorithm,
we use different number of clusters.
We may generate different
clustering results.
We may want to compare those results to,
for example,
we can use silhouette
coefficient to see how nicely,
by setting a certain number of clusters,
the clusters are better separated and
you, within each cluster
they are more compact so
this is a relative measure to
comparing different parameter setting.
[MUSIC]