[SOUND] In this session,
we will give a general
introduction on External Measures for
Clustering Validation.
We know clustering is unsupervised.
In this sense,
we really want to use some good judgement.
External methods is to give some
expert knowledge or some prior truths.
So to that extent,
we call these as ground truth T.
So given ground truth T, then we want
to measure the quality of clustering C,
we use the quality measure Q(C, T).
The function Q(CT) is good if it satisfies
the following four essential criteria.
The first one called cluster homogeneity.
That means we want the cluster
formed to be pure.
That means they're in the same cluster.
So, the purer the better, of course.
The second one,
called clustering completeness.
That means we want to assign objects
belonging to the same category in
the ground truth to the same cluster.
That means you may get all
these object are a category a,
but you assign them to two,
to three clusters.
That's no good.
We want to be complete.
The third on is rag bag better than alien.
Simply says,
you may have some heterogeneous object.
'Kay.
If you put them into a pure cluster,
you mix the other category up.
That's no good.
You want to penalize this.
It's better even to put
them into a rag bag.
Rag bag means it's in the miscellaneous or
other category.
It's better than you mix
up with some pure cluster.
Then the fourth measure of course,
small cluster preservation, simply says,
if you got a pretty small cluster already,
you do want to further split
them into pieces because those
pieces likely represent noises.
In that case, you better split
a larger category into smaller pieces.
The reason is, the larger category likely,
they may belong to different clusters,
or different other smaller categories.
That's small cluster preservation.
Then, we will see what we are going to
examine on those external measures.
We often use this graph, this color graph.
Those brown points,
this dark brown points, suppose they
are ground truth partitioning T1.
That means expert label
those points as T1, okay.
Then the ground truth, the other ground
truth may be they labeled as blue one.
That means T2 dark blue one,
actually is another category.
'Kay.
That means for ground truth, for expert,
they know that different colors
belong to different truths.
'Kay.
However your clustering algorithm
may generate things circled by
the light brown one or
orange one, or the red one.
That means they are not ideal,
they may not be good enough for
the matching what expert judgement.
So, we want to measure whether
your clustering method is good.
'Kay.
So, the measure one we call
matching-based measure.
We, we have sev, several measures, like
purity, maximum matching, or F-measure.
Another kind of measure called
entropy-based measures.
There are conditional entropy,
normalized mutual information,
NMI, or variation of information.
The certain kind of measures
called pairwise measures.
For example,
we may have four possibilities,
true positive, false negative.
False positive, true negative.
Okay.
Then, we actually have
Jaccard coefficient,
Rand statistic, Fowlkes-Mallow measure.
The fourth category called
correlation measures.
Essentially, they
are discretized Huber static and
normalized discretized Huber static.
And those marked as to be covered.
We will discuss them in more
detail in the subsequent sessions.
[MUSIC]