[SOUND].
In this session we are going
to introduce another group of
external measures called
entropy-based measures.
We know entropy is a very useful
information theory measure.
Not only is information theory
also used in data mining,
mission learning quite a lot.
Entropy essentially is representing
the amount of otherness
of the,
of the information in all the partitions.
So we still use this graph,
this figure to represent
conceptually we have ground truths
represented by different color points,
we have clusters represented
by different ellipses.
For entropy of clustering C.
Suppose we got R clusters.
It's, it's essentially this is
the entropy of every particular cluster.
Then we add all these clusters together
we get entropy for the clustering C.
Then for each cluster,
actually the entropy is based
on the probability of C sub i.
The probability of clustering
C sub i is based on the number
of points in this cluster divided
by the total number of points.
Then entropy of partitioning T is
essentially defined a similar way.
Suppose we have ground truths
j from 1 to k, these k groups.
Okay?
So for each ground truth is,
PT sub i we actually can get a,
the probability of the ground truth as
defined by these P sub t, sub i, okay.
Then we add all their
entropies together for
all the K ground truths we get a ground
truth for the whole partition.
Then what we're interested
in is the entropy of
T with respect to clustering C sub i.
That means we want to see how the ground
truth is distributed within each cluster.
So you probably can see this j
represent the ground truth, and
the i represents the really clusters.
So we probably want to
see such distribution so
we can work out the entropy of T
with respect to the cluster C sub i.
Then if we want to get to the conditional
entropy of T with respect
to whole clustering C,
then we just add all these together.
Because this one is just for
cluster C sub i, but
we total have r clusters, we add all
these up proportionally, then we will get
the whole conditional entropy of T with
respect to the whole clustering of C.
Conceptually, we can see the more of
a cluster's membership has split into
different partitions,
the higher the conditional entropy.
That's the less desirable.
You probably can see if,
if you're partitions, wide spread into
different clusters it is no good.
Okay.
For perfect clustering the conditional
entropy value should be 0.
The worse conditional entropy value,
is log k.
We can use a transformation
formula like this.
We can transfer on this
conditional entropy To be
the joint-entropy,
minus the clustering's entropy.
So, you probably can see, that's
the conditional formula transformation.
We're not getting to detail,
but you can check it.
Another very useful measure used for
external measure is
Normalized Mutual Information.
We use a similar figure
to sketch the idea.
The Mutual Information is also defined in,
information's theory, introduced there.
But it's also very useful in
machine learning and data mining.
Okay.
Essentially, the mutual information
quantifies the amount of shared
information, between the clustering C and
the partitioning T.
So you can probably see the formula, we
have r clusters, we have k ground truths.
So they are mutual information essentially
so adding all these up together.
This is a similar formula as entropy, but
it's different because you can probably
see this part is really, this ij's
probability divided by this cross rings
property and a partitioning's property.
That means we want to measure
the dependency between the observed joint
probability p sub ij of C and T,
and the expected joint probability
of PC sub i and PT sub j.
Under the independence assumption.
Of course, if c and
t are really independent that means
they really want equal distance to this.
Then you probably can see
this is one actually when
you take log this becomes 0, okay.
Of course in this case,
this is no good because it implies these
ground truths actually scatter
r around different clusters.
However there's no upper bound
on the mutual information,
which is less desirable.
That's why we need to introduce
a normalized mutual information.
That means we want to normalize the range
from 0 to the highest wines one.
Then the value close to 1 actually
indicates a good clustering, a value close
to 0 means they are almost accompanied
to random independent assignment.
Okay, then this normalized mutual
information essentially is you
take the mutual information.
Divide by the entropy of clustering and
divided by entropy of partitioning.
You product them together,
take their square root, or
you can transfer in this way.
So this is, quite useful,
because you will know once you're
clustering based on your external measure.
Your cluster becomes perfect if
their value is very close to one.
[MUSIC]