[SOUND] In this session,
we were introduce Internal Measures for
Clustering Validation.
Remember, we just discussed several
kinds of external measures.
The lucky thing for external
measure is we do have [INAUDIBLE].
We have expert knowledge,
we have a priors.
Unfortunately, in many cases,
we do not have [INAUDIBLE].
That's the reason we have to
rely on internal measures.
The internal measures based
on the concept of clustering.
It means we want the points
within the same cluster.
That means intra-cluster,
they are very compact.
They are close to each other and
we wanted points in different clusters
that means inter-cluster distance.
We want them as far apart as possible.
That means we want them
to be far separated.
That's the reason we want to maximizing
the intra-cluster compactness and
also maximizing the inter-cluster
separation, but
we want a tradeoff between these things.
So let's look at how we define this.
Suppose we give a clustering C with k
clusters, C sub 1to C sub k.
For each cluster C sub i,
it contains n sub i number of points.
Then we introduce the function W of S, R,
which is the sum of
the weights of all the edges
with one verdicts in S, the other in R.
For example, you'd get a two points.
You say, this point is in this cluster.
The other point is in the other cluster.
You want to look at their weight.
The weight usually can be defined
like a euclidean distance or
whatever you are using for clustering.
Then based on this, we can say,
the sum of all the intra-cluster
weights over all clusters
should be defined this way.
The reason is you can see this
is a C sub i, this is a C sub i.
That means both vertices are in the same
cluster, so that's why it's inter-cluster.
But at one point A and the other point B,
you actually use it will calculate twice,
because A to B, B to A,
you're actually calculating twice.
That's why you have to divide this by two.
Okay.
For all the clusters sum up
together is i from one to
the k's clusters,
then we define the sum of all the inter
cluster weights should
be calculated this way.
There, which is very obvious,
because one point,
one vertex is in the cluster C sub i and
the other one is not in the C sub i.
Simply say, in the other clusters,
that's why it's intro cluster.
But since the two points,
you calculate it twice,
that's why you have the divide by 2.
Then we sum up all these essentially,
it's i from one to k, all the clusters.
We get a Wout, okay?
That's the inter-cluster
weights sum them together.
Now we also can see the number
of distinct intra-cluster edges,
because for
i's cluster if n sub i number of points
there intra-cluster link,
you have end points choose two.
That's why you get this formula.
Then get all the clusters one to k,
you sum up, that's why you get n sub m.
Then for the inter-cluster
N sub out is notated by one
point is in cluster i,
the other point is cluster j.
They never are in the same cluster.
So you want to calculate all the edges,
among different clusters.
So that's the number of
distinct inter-cluster edges.
Then for BetaCV measure is
defined as Wi divided by N and
you can think this is the mean
intra-cluster distance and
you get Wout divided by number of out,
you can think is a mean
inter-cluster distance.
So the BetaCV essentially
the ratio of mean inter-cluster
distance versus the mean
intra-cluster distance.
Of course, for this measure is
the smaller, the better clustering.
Because a smaller means,
this is pretty small is quite a compact.
And this is the bigger,
it means it's more separated.
That's a BetaCV measure defined,
then we look at some other definition.
One popular use one called normalized cut.
Normalized cut is defined as follows.
The normalized cut of this ratio is
defined by sum up of all the k clusters.
For every cluster,
you calculate in this way or
more explicitly,
we can interpret in this way.
This is ways of the inter-cluster.
This is a weights to sum up of,
of the intra and inter-cluster weights.
And for this ratio,
you actually sum from i from one to k,
you'll get these normalized cut ratio.
Of course, based on this,
you want to the inter-cluster
to be far separated,
comparing to the intro one.
That's why the bigger normalized cut
value, the better the clustering.
Then there's another
definition called modularity.
This is especially popular for
graft clustering.
It is defined in this way.
You proceed, this part is the same
as normalized cut, cut formula.
Okay.
Like this, but
this part is the square of this.
Okay.
So that simply says,
this one is the observed
the fraction of the weights
within clusters.
This is the expected one.
So modularity, actually measured the
difference between the observed one and
the expected one.
So the smaller the value,
the better the clustering,
because the inter-cluster distance
are lower than the expected one.
So this is the modularity definition
used for graph clustering.
[MUSIC]