[SOUND] In this session, we are going to
introduce another kind of measures for
clustering validation called
the Relative Measures.
We already introduced external
measure when we have [INAUDIBLE].
We also introduced internal measure when
we try to measure the intro cluster,
they are very compact, and
inter cluster, they are far apart.
Now, we want to look at
what is relative measure.
Relative measure actually is trying
to direct compare different clusters.
Especially for those obtained
using the same algorithm but
different parameter setting.
For example, like if we all use k-means
to cluster a group of things but
in that case, we want to measure for
different cluster instantiation.
Which one gave you the best clustering or
a different case for
k from one to certain number,
which k gives you the best clustering.
In that case, we were measured
as using relative measure.
And, one interesting measure
called silhouette coefficient
can be used for relative measure, okay?
But, actually, silhouette coefficient
also popularly used as internal measure.
That means we will be able to use it to
check cluster cohesion and separation.
So, I first introduce it
as an internal measure
before I introduce it
as an external measure.
So for every point, x sub i,
we can calculate its silhouette
coefficient, s sub i, okay?
How we calculate it?
We use this formula this formula actually,
mu sub n,
is the mean distance to
the point of its own cluster.
Simply says, if we find this
point in the blue cluster, okay?
We're going to see this x sub i,
actually to all the points
in it's own cluster that
distance we want to reach them.
We get a mean distance that's mu sub n.
Then what is mu sub out's mean, okay?
That means we want to see this
blue point to its closest
cluster which is this orange one,
to its closest cluster.
All the points its closest cluster,
we calculate their mean distance,
that's this value, mu sub out mean, okay?
Then what we want to
see is their distance,
you probably can clearly see for
any point x sub i.
You want that the internal distance,
its rhythm is small but
even to its closest cluster,
this average reason be big.
So, to that extent, this value usually
should be positive and
the more positive the better, okay?
Then we, we normalize it, we divide by the
maximum value between this mu out mean.
And the mu n, and
if we pick up the two, so
it simply says that this division
must be smaller than one.
But on the other hand, if this cluster
to one, simply says, it's better because
the internal is very compact to
the outside is the reasonably big.
This is only for one point,
what is for the whole clustering?
Okay, so silhouette coefficient for
the whole clustering is you
take all the end points.
You calculate every one's
silhouette coefficient s sub i.
I from 1 to n you calculate all
the s sub i, you normalize it,
you divide it by the number of points n.
You get the whole clusterings
silhouette coefficient.
Of course, these silhouette coefficient,
if it's closer to plus 1, it,
it implies good clustering.
Because the internal one to its own points
is rather close to the other cluster,
even to the closest one, is really far.
So we also can use this silhouette
coefficient as a relative measure.
For example, we can use it to estimate
the number of clusters in the data, say,
what is the best of k.
We can pick a value that yield the best
at clustering, that means yielding
the high value for SC and SC sub i, okay?
For example, you can, thinking about,
you did a lot of clustering, okay?
For all the i's, you want to see which
one give you the best clustering?
That means which one gives you
the highest silhouette coefficient?
Then you can pick up that instantiation,
pick that k.
So that's the usage of silhouette
coefficient as a relative measure.
[MUSIC]