[SOUND] In this session,
we are going to study another issue for
clustering assessment
called Cluster Stability.
Cluster stability basically say,
whether you got the right parameter,
you get the very stable
clustering results.
That means you can assume you get
the data set D, you take a sample
get several datasets from the same
data set D, you do the clustering.
And you should assume if you're clustering
finally get a very stable clustering
results, that's a good clustering.
Usually, you can use this to
find a good parameter values for
a given clustering algorithm.
For example, you can find a good value of
k, which is a good number of clusters.
So how do you find this?
You probably just look at this graph,
you probably can see.
If you set k as three or even as two,
you probably can find it
quite reasonable clusters.
But if you set as four or five,
no matter how smart you are,
probably this cluster you
find may not be quite stable.
So to that extent, you may try
to test the cluster's stability,
we introduce one method
called Bootstrapping approach
to find the best value of k,
judged based on stability.
How can we do this?
This Bootstrapping basically says,
from D, you take tt samples of size n,
but the,
the sampling is sampling with replacement.
Then it's every time you take almost
from the same D, you take it t times.
Then you get to the sample D sub 1,
D sub to D sub j to D sub t.
Okay.
Then when you run the same
clustering algorithm with k
value from two to the maximum
of the k you like.
Okay.
Then you can compare the distance
between all the pairs of clustering.
For example, for each k,
you may try to see whether the D sub i and
D sub j,
these two different sample datasets.
You will see whether finer you get the,
the sample,
you want to compute the expected
pairwise distance for each value of k.
That means suppose k you get a ten,
you get at least ten clusters,
you want to see their pairwise distance.
Okay.
Then what you can see is this value k,
if it exhibits the least
deviation between clustering.
That means you do clustering
those sample D sub i or
sample D sub j,
they have the least deviation.
Okay.
That k should be the most stable one.
Thus, you may want to have this k value.
That's one application to test
the cluster stability to find the best k.
Actually, there are many methods to find
the k, the appropriate number of clusters.
One method called empirical method,
actually people give you
this empirical formula.
For example, for
total data sets of n points,
you may take the square root
of half of this n points.
Okay.
For example, if n is 200,
the expected value you will need to
get number of clusters should be 10.
Of course, this may work out for
a small number of points.
If you get a really big number of points,
for example, you get a,
too many points, then you get this value,
you'll get a k as a solvent,
probably you may not want to get a solvent
clusters even for too many points.
Another method,
people use called elbow method.
Elbow method means you tried
to based on the number of
clusters that go one, two, three, four.
You get number of clusters, then you get
it, the sum of the within square variance.
That means you just to look at the average
of within to cluster variance,
you try to look at this to see,
know what is the best,
the number of k that you want to see
the elbow point, the turning point.
So that's one method.
Another method of finding the best
number k is use cross validation.
That means you divide
a given dataset into m parts.
So you take one part as a test data,
the remaining part to do the clustering.
Okay.
You can do this m times, so
you can check their overall
quality of the clustering.
Then how we test the,
the quality of the examples?
Okay.
What we do is, is, supposed we use this
m minus 1 parts to do the clustering,
we find the k clusters.
Then for each point in the testing set,
you try to find the,
it's closest centroid.
Then you, based on this, you try to
find for all the points in the datasets,
you try to find the sum
of the square distance.
That means you try to find some of
the square error SSE, as we introduced.
Then usually, you try to see whether this,
you get the best fit of the test datasets.
That means you get the smallest
sum of square distance.
Since for
cross validation you repeat this m times,
so then what you can do is
you can compare the overall
quality measure with
respect to different k's,
then you'll find what is the best
number to fit the data best?
That means you get
the overall quality measure,
you get the lowest SSE for
this particular k.
Usually, this is the right
number of clusters.
[MUSIC]