[SOUND] In this session,
we're going to study
another important issue
called clustering tendency.
What is clustering tendency?
That means we want to study whether the
data sets we have really contain clusters.
Whether data contains some
inherent grouping structures.
Otherwise, even use random generated data,
you may find a certain number of clusters.
However, it does not really make sense.
That means we want to assess whether
the data is suitable for clustering.
However, to determine
the clustering tendency, or
clusterability, is a hard task.
Just because there are so
many definitions of clusters.
For example, we studied partitioning
methods, hierarchical methods,
density-based methods,
graph-based methods.
All these different methods may have
different definitions of clusters.
That's why to study whether the data
is clusterable or not is pretty hard.
However, even we just
fix the cluster type.
For example,
we just study the partitioning methods,
it is still hard to define an appropriate
null model for a data set.
However, there are still some studies
on clusterability assessment.
For example, there are methods
like spatial histogram method,
distant distribution method,
a Hopkins statistic.
The general philosophies, they try to
compare their measure with the measure
generate from random samples,
to see whether they are rather different.
For example, for spatial histogram
method is try to contrast
the histogram of data with the histogram
generated from the random sample to
see whether they are rather different.
For distance distribution is try to
compare the pairwise point distance from
the data, and the pairwise distance
from the randomly generated samples.
Hopkins Statistic is to use a sparse
sampling test for spatial randomness.
And since they carry quite similar spirit
we will only introduce one
spatial histogram method.
For spatial histogram approach,
the general philosophy is
we try to construct a d-dimensional
histogram of the input.
For example, this is the two d we
may constructed two dimensional
histogram for the input dataset D.
With the histogram generated
from random samples.
That means we want compare the figure
generated from the left and
that generated from the right figure.
Okay, the data is clusterable
if these two histogram
distributions are rather different.
That means they really generate
very different distributions,
then likely this dataset is clusterable,
okay?
The concrete method is we try to divide
each dimension into equal waste bins.
Then we try to see each cell here,
how many points are in the cell.
Now we can generate an empirical joint
probability mass function, okay?
Then for the random generate data sets,
we'll do the same.
We'll generate empirical joint
probability mass function.
Then what we will do is we try
to compare whether these two,
they differ quite a lot.
That means we're going to
compare how much they differ.
The typical method is
we use KL divergence.
That means we calculate
the KL divergence value.
The KL divergence is Kullback-Leibler
divergence is defined
based on some formulas.
I'm now going to introduce
the detail of KL divergence.
If you want to learn more,
you can check any textbook in statistics
or mission learning or data mining.
In general they introduce this measure.
Then you'll find if they
are very different.
Then, from the random samples, then you
will say this data set is clusterable.
Finally, I'm going to introduce
a few textbooks, chapters,
or general papers, that discuss
the clustering validation measures.
Especially what he shows this way is
a summary of many research papers.
And Zaki's book gives a lot
of details on other measures
we did not cover in this lecture.
Thank you.
[MUSIC]