[SOUND]
We
first discuss how to mine
Multi-level Association Rules.
Multi-level Association rules come
down to a very natural setting.
For example, to your boss if you say,
now I find milk and
bread sold together, probably
everybody thinks this is common sense.
But if you find 2% milk
with a brand Dairyland sold
together with Wonder Wheat Bread, probably
it becomes something more interesting.
But if you see this Dairyland 2% milk
actually sitting in the hierarchy, the top
level could be milk, then go down to 2%
milk then go down to Dairyland 2% milk.
So, it is interesting to mine
Multi-level Association Rule patterns.
Then the interesting thing becomes
how to set a min-support threshold?
While we set up uniform min-support
threshold across all the levels.
But there's one problem,
if you set it very high
because they naturally have lower support,
the low-level patterns will not show up.
But if you set it very low
the high level you get too many
interesting patterns because
everything may show up.
So a reasonable way is set
Level-reduced min-support.
That means items at higher level use
higher level min-support like 5%,
where you go down to the lower level, you
may adopt lower level min-support like 1%.
To that extent,
the skim milk will show up.
But at high levels, some you know peanuts
or some other things may not show up
if they are not interesting,
they are not frequent at all.
So then the problem is if we
set a multi-level minimum
support thresholds associated with
different levels then how can we
use one scan in one shot we
mine all the different levels?
The interesting thing could be we
can use shared multi-level mining.
We can use the lowest min-support to let
the high level pass down to the low level.
But in the meantime when we analyze
rules and analyze patterns,
we can fill out the higher level rules
using higher level support threshold.
So another problem for mining Multi-level
Association Rules is redundancy.
Because the rules may have
some hidden relationships.
For example, suppose 2% milk sold is
about 1/4 of total milk sold in gallons.
Then if you see these two rules,
one and two, the Rule (1) says,
milk implies wheat bread which is
supports is 8% and the confidence, 70%.
The Rule (2), if you drop down
a little down to from milk to 2% milk.
In the meantime the support also
dropped down correspondingly, for
example from 8% to 2%,
Un that case, people can see.
Rule (2) is a redundant because we
can derive such things from Rule (1).
That means,
if the rule can be derived from the higher
level rules that lower level rules
are redundant, we shall remove them.
Another interesting thing is
different kinds of items.
Inherently, many different
support thresholds.
For example, you go to Walmart,
you may see diamond, watch, or
some expensive things that more valuable
but they sold maybe less frequent.
But milk and
bread probably sold very frequent.
So, if we set min-support for
all kinds of items using the same
minimum support threshold.
Then the valuable items may
be easily feared out, so,
to that extent it is necessary to have
customized minimum support settings for
different kinds of items.
Instead of taking each item try
to decide ib minimum support,
we can use group-based,
individualized, min-support.
For example, we can group,
diamond, watch, or
some expensive things
set a lower min-support.
Take a milk and bread,
those frequent things, and
set up higher min-support threshold.
Then the question becomes how to
mine such patterns efficiently.
Actually, if we take our previous study,
the scalable pattern mining methods,
we can easily extend them by adding
different minimum support threshold.
I would not discuss the detail, but
I think it could be a good exercise.
[MUSIC]