Now we come down to another interesting issue,
it's mining multi-dimensional association rules.
Sometimes the items or the things
we want to mine are actually sitting on the multi-dimensions.
The single dimension rule we studied,
for example, X buys milk,
then X buys bread.
Milk and bread, both are from the same kind of dimension
called product but sometimes we may get a multi-dimensional association rules.
For example, for this inter-dimensional association rule,
like if X age is 18 to 25 and
if X occupation is a student then likely X going to buy a Coke.
That was actually H, occupation,
and items to buy are three different dimensions.
That kind of rule we call inter-dimensional association rule.
Then even we look at this sometimes we see the Hybrid cases,
like if X age is 18 to 25,
if X buys popcorn likely X is going to buy coke.
That kind of rule you have H as
one dimension but these two buys are seeing the same damages.
Okay. So if you see this kind of cases,
they likely these three different cases may slightly need different kind of algorithms.
Another thing is that attributes can be categorical, can be numerical.
For example, the categorical case could be product like
beer and diapers and you may have a profession like a student or a professor.
So, for these categorical attributes
we can for multi-dimensional, inter-dimensional association rules,
we can construct a data cube to mine
such things or just use data cube structure to mine such association efficiently.
Then, another case could be
quantitive attributes or we can say those attributes are numerically.
For example, H [inaudible] or some other things.
For this case it's quite often we may use this criterization method, clustering method,
some kind of gradient approaches we are going to discuss this part
in the quantitative association rule of mining. Thank you.