[SOUND] Now we are going to
discuss another interesting
problem, mining compressed patterns.
We know frequent pattern mining may
often generate many many patterns.
But in many of such patterns
may share some similarity.
Maybe there is scattered, but not so
meaningful if you generate
all those patterns.
Let's look at such an example.
Suppose we finally get five pattern IDs.
So you perceive these five
patterns are like P1 and P2.
They are very similar and
their supports are also very similar.
But P2 and P3,
they are similar in item sets but
their supports are rather different.
Can we compress them?
When we first examine closed patterns,
actually for
closed pattern,
there's nothing you can compress.
The reason is closed pattern
require the supports are identical,
then you can compress them.
But none of them have
identical support counts.
So nothing can be compressed.
What about max pattern?
Of course we can use max pattern,
that's P3, to represent all the patterns.
But on the other hand you probably see P3,
this support,
is rather different from all the others.
To use P3 you may lose a lot of
information on the support of
other patterns.
So that desired output
actually is P2 P3 and P4.
The reason you probably can see is P1 and
P2, they share a similar item sets and
also they share very
similar support counts.
So we may need a good measure to
see what things can be compressed.
A good measure could be
pattern distance measure.
We use this definition to
define the pattern distance.
You probably can look at a P1 and
P2 when we look at this.
P1 and P2, their transaction,
intersection of their transaction ID.
What should be the count?
The number of transactions they can
intersect, actually it's a smaller one
here, because every transaction
containing P2 must also contain P1.
So their support counts intersection
should be this number, okay?
What about the unit?
The unit actually says all those
transactions, because we know all
the transactions, P1 must also
containing the transactions of P2.
So their unit number should
be this number, okay?
In that case,we perceive these
two numbers very close to one.
Then the distance 1 minus
this very close to 1 number,
you get something very close to 0.
That means their pattern
distance is rather small.
Based on this,
we probably can see we may be able
to define a theta clustering or
theta cover.
That means if we can see the pattern P,
the theta cover of pattern P
is finding those patterns,
all the pattern can be expressed by this,
the distance is within delta.
Actually, you probably see, P2 is a good
one, because P2 essentially can cover P1,
because P1 just have a little less item
sets, but their support is so close.
To that extent we may say they
are within this theta cover.
So for data clustering,
we will be able to cluster P1 P2 together
using P2 to represent the pattern.
So that means if we do
this data clustering,
then all the patterns in the cluster
can be represented by one pattern, P.
So the problem becomes whether we should
mine all the patterns then compress them,
or should directly mine
these compressed patterns.
Actually there's a efficient method
which can directly mine those compressed
patterns.
I'm not going to get into the detail but
you may refer to this interesting paper.
Okay, then another interesting thinking
is Redundancy-Aware Top-k Patterns.
That means we want to get a desired
pattern which is similar to the compressed
one, because want to get high
significance and low redundancy.
These kind of of set up patterns, okay.
Let's look at this a, b, c, d,
four different kind of compression.
Actually a is a set of original patterns.
There are cluster shields,
their pattern distance, and the color
the darker shows is more significant,
the lighter shows is less significant.
Okay, in that case you probably
can see in this bigger cluster,
there are three patterns.
They are quite significant.
If you just do the top-k pattern mining,
that means you take it as a support count,
or other significant measure,
you would only find these three patterns.
Suppose we wanted only find top three,
then all the remaining
patterns like here in the other
cluster is completely missing.
But if you say I just do the
summarization, try to find no clusters.
And within each cluster
try to find their centers.
Then you'll pretty well find those
less significant patterns, so
this may not be a good balance.
Actually better balance is you take care
of both significance and the redundancy.
Simply says, you look at this one,
there is something very significant.
And that they are also
in the cluster center
you may want to show these patterns.
In the meantime,
suppose you can only show three,
you may show these are significant and
less redundant.
This one is significant and
also it represents this cluster.
So the problem becomes how
to develop efficient and
effective method finding such
redundancy aware top-k patterns.
There's an interesting study
which uses the max marginal
significance to measure the combined
significance of a pattern and
develop efficient methods
to mine such patterns.
We are not going to get
into detail of this method.
Interested readers we made
read the paper we pointed out.
Thank you.
[MUSIC]