[SOUND] First, we are going to
discuss Sequential Pattern and
Sequential Pattern Mining, the concept.
So the first thing is we should say,
sequential pattern mining is very useful,
has very broad applications.
One application could be in
costumer shopping sequences.
For example, you get a loyalty card for
your shops, you may want to see.
Maybe one costumer likely
going to first buy a laptop,
then a digital camera,
then a smartphone within 6 months.
If this forms a pattern, you may be able
to try to do some kind of advertisement
to other similar customers or serving
some new incentive for this customer.
Like a medical treatment form sequences,
natural disasters like earthquake
happening it may have some sequences
of natural and also human phenomenon.
Science engineering a lot
of things are processes.
They evolve along with time.
Similarly, stocks markets they have
some kind of duration of sequences.
Weblog click streams,
calling patterns for telephones and
other things forming sequences.
Even for software engineering, the program
execution from sequential patterns.
The biological sequences very, very
useful for analysis like DNA sequences,
protein sequences.
So we see trying to get
sequential patterns out of those
very big vast applications,
could be very useful and important.
Actually, we can distinguish
transaction databases,
usually may not be important
to look at their time effect.
Sequence databases,
they have a time stamp attached with it.
Time-series databases, usually the time,
things happened actually along the even or
equivalent time intervals.
Sometimes, it's very consecutive.
Then for sequential patterns,
actually there are two kinds.
One is gapped, another is non-gapped.
The gapped pattern means, you do allow
to have gaps within those patterns.
The non-gapped patterns means,
you will not allow these patterns,
the sequence, everything is important.
The concept of this important
if you have gapped and
you have to trade them very seriously.
For example, for shopping transactions.
Probably, you don't care customer in
the middle buying some other things, so
it's not important to study the gaps.
Click streams sometimes you may say, some
click streams, you may care about gaps.
Some, you probably do not
care of gaps that much.
For biological sequences,
in many case you do carry gaps, so
the protein sequence or DNA sequences,
if you insert many things, in
the middle of the two DNA sets, sometimes
you may completely change the function.
So let's look at the customer
shopping sequence
as a major example to study how
to do sequential pattern mining.
Sequential pattern mining essentially is,
you give me a set of sequences.
The algorithm is trying to find
the complete set of frequent sub-sequences
satisfying a certain
minimum support threshold.
Let's look at this example.
We have a sequence database containing
four customer shopping sequences.
Okay, what's the meaning of this?
We look at this particular sequence.
This sequence, the parenthesis means this
one is within the same shopping basket.
Then after that, you get another one
ab that means this ab following ef.
But ab is getting together
at the same time.
Similarly, df getting together but
following ab, and then c, then b, okay.
That means each one of these
you can think is a element.
It may contain a set of items or
you call events.
Then this one event may
follow another one.
The items within the event, the order is
not important because they are in the same
shopping basket but for our convenience,
we can sort them alphabetically.
Then what is subsequence?
Actually any sub-strings within this line
probably can see here
the subsequence you may have a gap.
For example, you say, you can have a,
you have bc, bc actually you chop this a.
You can chop complete ac, then you get d.
You can chop one f, you can get it c.
So, this one is a subsequence
of this longer sequence.
Then, sequential pattern mining,
the sequential pattern essentially is
if you set a support,
like a minimum support is 2,
that means, at least 2 sequences
contain the subsequence.
You find those subsequence,
this is a sequential pattern.
For example, ab getting together then c,
in this sequence database,
this is a pattern of support 2.
So sequential pattern mining algorithm is,
you try to develop algorithms
which are efficient, scalable and
these algorithms should find the complete
set of frequent subsequences.
What we call sequential patterns.
And also should be able to incorporate
various kinds of user-defined constraints.
For sequential pattern mining,
actually Apriori property,
the property we have used in
frequent pattern mining still holds.
For example, if we say a subsequence
s sub 1 is infrequent,
then any of this supersequence
cannot be frequent.
So that's almost the same idea as Apriori.
So based on this idea, we actually
can develop lots of algorithms.
One, represented the algorithm called GSP,
Generalized Sequential Pattern mining,
developed in 1996.
Another way is a Vertical
format-base mining called SPADE,
developed in year 2000.
The third one we're going to introduce
is Pattern-growth methods called
PrefixSpan developed in year 2001.
And then we are going to study mining
closed sequential patterns called CloSpan.
Finally, we're going to discuss
constraint-based sequential pattern
mining.
[MUSIC]