[SOUND].
Now I am going to introduce you
another algorithm called SPADE,
which is sequential pattern mining
based on vertical data format.
You probably still remember the vertical
data format based frequent pattern mining
algorithm called ECLAD.
Here for the same set of authors,
they actually develop an interesting
algorithm for sequential pattern mining.
Okay.
The idea is pretty simple.
If you take the Sequence,
you do a little detailed study,
you get a Sequence ID,
Element ID, and set of Items.
So, what you can see is, for
the first Sequence ID, 1.
Element ID 1, you find item a.
Element ID 2, you find a,
b, c so on, okay.
Then we can transform this
into vertical format.
That means we just look at the,
where a occurs and where the b occurs.
So the a occurs, you probably can see,
it happens in Sequence 1, ElementID 1.
In Sequence 1, Element 2, and
also Sequence 1, Element 3.
So you get this one the same.
You can get Sequence ID 2, 3, 4.
Similarly for b, you can find where
the b comes, is Sequence 1, Element 2.
So you get 1, 2.
Then how we can combine them into frequent
sequences, like a then b, or b then a.
If you say a then b, you,
you will be requiring a is in front of b,
or a's Element ID is in
front b's Element ID.
That means for
the same Sequence ID 1, if EID 1 is
smaller than EID 2 of b,
then you get 1 Sequence E ab.
Similarly, for b then a,
what you get is these
Element ID of b should be
smaller than Element ID of a.
For the same reason you can get
all of them for the lines 2, okay.
So for lines 3 what you need is,
you just get lines 2 frequent 1s.
Then you do drawing.
How do you do drawing?
You probably can see these
Element ID Sequence ID should be the same.
The Element ID, this b shared with this b,
they are both 2.
So you can join them together,
you get 1, 2, 3 here.
And you join the other together,
you can get a 1, 3, 4 because it,
Element 2, you get a,
you get a b, you can get a again.
So, the two lines and
you actually can find all of them, okay.
So that's a reason you can
use Apriori based principle
to find all the frequent subsequences.
This algorithm was developed
by Zaki in 2001 called SPADE.
It's Sequential Pattern Discovery
using Equivalent Class.
[MUSIC]