So in module three,
we're going to be visualizing data that
doesn't have coordinates
associated with it explicitly.
That means we're going to have to
derive the coordinates from the data,
through analysis, through mathematics,
and specifically through linear algebra.
So if you don't have experience
with linear algebra, don't worry.
I'm going to be going into a lot of
details involving linear algebra and
other mathematical techniques for
people that understand those techniques so
that they can implement these algorithms.
But if you don't have experience
with those techniques,
with this area of mathematics,
that's fine.
We're not going to be quizzed on it.
You're not going to be
required to implement it for
the project at the end of the week.
We have tools that will provide that for
you, so just bear with us.
And you'll get an appreciation for
the tools that are used to
lay out data when we don't have
coordinates assigned to it.
[MUSIC]