The first session is on
what is Cluster Analysis?
To understand what is cluster analysis,
we should know first what is a cluster?
A cluster is actually
a collection of data objects,
those objects are similar
within the same cluster.
That means the objects are similar to
one another within the same group.
And they are rather different,
or they are dissimilar, or
unrelated, to the objects in other
groups or in other clusters.
Okay, then cluster analysis which
is also called clustering or
data segmentation, the essential is
getting a set of tape data points.
The cluster analysis is to partition them
into a set of clusters, or set of groups.
They are as similar as possible
within the same group and
as far apart as possible
among different groups.
Cluster analysis is unsupervised learning,
in the sense there's
no predefined classes.
This is very different from classification
which needs supervised learning or
needs to give in the class labors then you
can construct the classification models.
There are many ways to use
our apply cluster analysis,
essentially cluster analysis can
either provide as a stand alone
tool to get insight into your
data distribution like a summary.
Or you can serve, you can use it
to serve as pre-processing step or
intermediate step for other algorithms,
like a classification or
a prediction or like many other tasks,
including data mining and
other applications.
Thank you.
[MUSIC]