[SOUND] Hi, in this session, we're going
to discuss applications
of cluster analysis.
Cluster analysis has lots of applications.
For example, it has been properly
used as pre-processing step or
intermediate step for
other data mining tasks.
For example, you can generate complex
summary of data for classification,
pattern discovery, hypothesis
generation and testing and many others.
And it also has been popularly used for
outlier detection,
because outliers can be considered those
points that are far away from any cluster.
Cluster analysis also has been used for
data summarization,
compression and reduction.
For example, in im, image processing,
vector quantization has been using
cluster analysis quite a lot.
Cluster analysis also can be used for
collaborative filtering,
recommendation systems or
customer segmentation,
because clusters can be used to find
like-minded users or similar products.
Cluster analysis also has been used for
trend detection, for dynamic data.
For example, we can cluster stream data or
detecting trends and
patterns in dynamic data strings.
And cluster analysis also has been
used for multimedia data analysis,
biological data analysis and
social network analysis.
For example, we can use cluster
clustering methods to cluster images or
videos or audio clips or
we can use cluster analysis on genes and
protein sequences and
many other interesting tasks.
Thank you.
[MUSIC]