[MUSIC]
In this session we're going
to study the requirements and
challenges of cluster analysis.
There are many things to considered for
cluster analysis.
For example,
the first one people are often to
consider is partitioning criteria.
That means whether we want
to get a single level or
multiple-level hierarchical partitioning.
In many cases,
multi-level hierarchical partitioning or
what we call hierarchical clustering
could be quite desirable.
The second thing we
want to consider whether
how the clusters can separate the objects.
It can be hard or exclusive,
or soft, non-exclusive.
The exclusive means one object,
like one customer,
can belong to only one region, okay.
Non-exclusive, for example, one document
may belong to more than one cluster.
Then for a similarity measure,
there could be many different
kinds of similarity measures.
For example,
distance-based using Euclidean space or
a road network or vector space.
Or we can use connectivity-based, for
example, based on density or contiguity.
The fourth one that we are going
to discuss is clustering space.
That means, whether we want to
do full space clustering, or
we want to do subspace clustering.
Full space means especially in the low
dimensional, for example in 2D,
two dimensional space,
in the area or in the region,
whether we want to find the clusters
in those region, in the full 2D space.
Or only we want to project
on the 1D subspace.
However in many high
dimensional clustering,
it is hard to find meaningful
clusters in a very high damage space.
But it is possible to find interesting
clusters in the subspaces.
For example, in the corresponding
lower dimensional space.
So the subspace clustering
also becomes very important.
Then, for cluster analysis, there
are many requirements and challenges.
The first, most important thing
is the quality of clustering.
Means whether we are going to deal
with different kinds of attributes,
numerical one, categorical data,
text, multimedia data,
networks, or a mixture of multiple types.
Whether we can discover
clusters with arbitrary shape,
like an oil spill, or whether we will
be able to deal with noisy data.
Then the second important issue
people consider is scalability.
That means whether we will be able in
a very big amount of data environment,
whether we can cluster all the data or
we must draw some sample and
cluster only on the sample rate.
Whether we can handle
high dimensional data, or
we can only project them
in the low dimension space.
And whether we can do timely incremental
clustering, especially for data streams.
Whether we can do stream clustering.
Especially whether the cluster results
may not be sensitive to
the input order of the data.
Another important issue we need to
handle is constraint-based clustering.
That means users usually have their
own thinking on the preference or
constraints of the cluster
they want to derive.
They may have domain knowledge.
They may know certain subspaces
could be more interesting.
They may even raise queries.
So can we handle clustering given
user preference or constraints?
The final issue we are going to discuss
is interpretability and usability.
Simply says the clustering
whether they can derive
meaningful clusters which
can be understood by people,
can be used by many applications,
can interpret data nicely.
All these are a very important issue
we are going to study in this lecture.
[MUSIC]