[SOUND] In this session,
we're going to provide a multi-dimensional
categorization of cluster analysis.
Cluster analysis can be
viewed in many different way.
We will provide a multi-dimensional
categorization on all the different
methods.
The first categorization
is based on techniques,
based on different techniques
employed in cluster analysis.
We can consider these
are density-based methods or
they are distance-based methods or
grid-based methods or
probabilistic generative
model based methods.
Or we are essentially using
dimensionality reduction measures
to reduce the dimensions before
we do effective clustering or
we can directly perform high
dimensional clustering or
whether the measures are scalable for
large data analysis.
And the second categorization
is based on data type-centered.
So that means different kinds
of data types likely were used,
rather different clustering methods.
For example, how to cluster
numerical data, category data,
text data, multimedia data,
time-series data,
sequence data, stream data,
network data or uncertain data.
The third categorization is whether we can
provide additional insights for
clustering.
For example,
we can provide a visual insights or
we can incorporate some kind of
semi-slightly supervision or
we can use ensemble-based measures or
we can use validation-based measures.
All these, we're going to get into
more detail in the next sessions.
Thank you.
[MUSIC]