[SOUND]
Hi, in this session we are going to
provide a brief overview of
typical clustering methodologies.
There are many clustering methods.
They can be roughly categorized into
a few clustering methodologies.
The first method's called
distance-based methods.
Essentially there are two
kinds of methods.
One called partitioning algorithms,
the other we call hierarchical algorithms.
Partitioning algorithms essentially is,
partitioning the data in a high
dimension space, into multiple clusters.
The typical methods include K-Means,
K-Medoids,
K-Medians, those methods
we are going to introduce.
For hierarchical algorithms, essentially
we can either do an agglomerative,
or we call bottom-up,
merging many points into clusters,
merging small clusters into bigger ones,
then from hierarchical clusters.
Or we can use divisive methods.
Start with a single big,
all the data is encased in one cluster,
then we try to split them,
divide them using the top-down splitting,
into smaller and smaller clusters.
And then the second methodology,
called density-based methods.
The third one called grid-based methods.
Of course they have some linkages as well.
Density-based method essentially is,
we can think the database space,
made at a high-level granularity,
may you think about it with certain grade,
or
certain structures, or certain k nearest
neighbors, we may find certain density.
For the dense small regions,
we can merge them into bigger regions.
In this way,
we will be able to find clusters,
those events regions,
with arbitrary shape.
The grid-based method,
essentially is partitioning the data
space into grid-like structures.
Each grid is a summary of
the characteristics of the data,
in the lower grid or lower cells.
Then the third method is called
probabilistic and generative models,
that means we can model data
from a generative process.
We can assume underneath, there
are certain distributions, for example,
mixture of Gaussians, okay?
Then with the data,
we can think the current points
are generated from these
underlying generative model,
or underlying generative mechanisms.
Then we can model parameters,
using a Expectation-Maximization
algorithm we are going to introduce.
Based on the available data sets, we may
try to find the maximum likelihood fit.
And based on this fit,
we will be able to estimate the generative
probability of the underlying data points.
And based on this, we may find the models.
Then, in many cases the data may be
sitting in a high-dimensional space.
We may need to study
high-dimensional clustering methods.
One influential method
called subspace clustering,
essentially you try to find
the clusters on various subspaces.
So, that method can be categorized
into bottom-up methods,
top-down high-dimensional clustering
method, or correlation-based methods.
We will also introduce some interesting
method, a delta clustering.
Then, for high-dimensional clustering,
there are many methods developed for
dimensionality reduction.
Essentially is we can
think the height dimension
is in a vertical form there,
containing lots of columns.
And for those columns,
when we perform clustering,
essentially the columns are clustered,
the rows or
columns can be clustered together,
we call co-clustering.
There are several typical methods.
One is probabilistic
latent semantic indexing.
Later, people develop another method
called Latent Dirichlet Allocation.
So PLSI or LDA, are typical topic
modeling methods for text data.
Essentially, we can think the text can
be clustered into multiple topics.
Each topic is a cluster, and each topic
is associated with a set of words, or
we can think of they are dimensions.
And also a set of documents, you can
think they are rows, simultaneously.
And the second popular
study method's called
nonnegative matrix factorization, NMF.
This is a kind of co-clustering
method you can think as,
you'll get a nonnegative
matrix because the word,
a word frequencies in documents
are nonnegative, okay?
They are zero or more, but
they are nonnegative values in the matrix.
For this nonnegative matrix,
we can approximately
factorize it into two nonnegative
lower ranked matrices,
type U and V,
that will reduce the number of dimensions.
Another very interesting
method we're going to study
is called spectral clustering.
That means we use a spectrum of
the similarity matrix of the data,
to perform dimensionality reduction.
The higher dimension
reduced into the lower,
fewer dimensions, then we can perform
clustering in fewer dimensions.
That's spectral clustering methods.
In this course, we are going to
study many low-dimension and
high-dimension clustering methods, and
study their different variations,
and applications as well.
[MUSIC]