[SOUND]
Hi, in this session
we are going to give a brief overview
on clustering different types of data.
We encounter various
kinds of types of data.
For example,
the early clustering algorithm most times
with the design was on numerical data.
And the second type of data is category
data, including the binary that
most people consider as also can be
handled in categorical data or category.
For example, gender, race, zip code, or
market-basket data,
you would consider the data is discrete.
There's no natural order, but
certain kind of data is text data,
this is very popular in social media,
on the Web, or social networks.
Usually if we consider
a word as one dimension,
then we are handling very high dimensional
data, but they are very sparse.
Their value usually corresponding
to word frequencies.
The methods to handle such data,
include a combination of k-means and
agglomarative method, topical modelling
methods, or co-clustering methods.
We are going to discuss
this extensive later.
Multimedia data is another
kind of data needs clustering.
Usually images, audio, video,
those are Flickr and
YouTube actually are multimedia data.
They are multi-modal in a sense.
They have image, audio, video, many cases
they have text, as captions as well.
We can consider data are contextual data,
they contain both behavioral and
the contextual attributes.
For example for images,
we can consider the position of a pixel
represents its context,
the value represents its behavior.
For video and music data,
we can consider temporal ordering of
the records represents its meaning.
Time-series data is another
popularly encountered data
like in sensors, stock markets,
temporal tracking, or
forecasting, those task
are usually handled time-series.
Time-series, we usually consider
data are temporally dependent.
They are consecutive,
usually the interval is somehow equal.
Like, we can consider time
as contextual attributes,
data value as behavioral attribute.
Usually such analysis include
correlation-based online analysis,
like online clustering of
stocks to find stock tickers.
Or we use shape-based offline analysis,
for example,
we can cluster ECG based
on overall shapes.
Sequence data is another kind of data.
Usually in weblog analysis,
or biological sequence
analysis, or analyze the system commands.
These, we can think the placement rather
than time, the contextual attribute.
That means where they are.
Then the similarity function,
include Hamming distance, edit distance,
longest common subsequences.
The clustering method, we call sequence
clustering may use suffix tree,
may use generative model,
like Hidden Markov Model.
Stream data is another kind of data.
Stream data can be considered
as a real-time data,
like water flowing in and out.
It may evolve a long time.
It may have concept shifts
because stream coming and go.
So, we need a single pass algorithm,
rather you can see it again and again.
And the typical method for stream
clustering could be micro-clustering,
that means we need to create efficient
intermediate representation by some
kind of a micro-clustering method.
Graphs and homogeneous networks
is another kind of data.
This then kind of data usually,
so-called homogeneous networks that
means we consider networks as graphs,
the nodes and
edges actually are of one kind, one type.
Actually any kind of data
can be modeled as a graph
with the nodes as different attributes and
entries, and
edge graph in their similarity values.
The typical method for handling graph
clustering could be generative models,
combinatorial algorithm like graph cuts,
spectral clustering method,
non-negative matrix factorization methods.
Then a little bit beyond homogeneous
network are heterogeneous networks.
This kind of network consists of
multiple types of nodes and edges.
Like a bibliographical data, hospital,
handling disease, patients, doctors, and
treatments to cluster different
kinds of nodes and links together.
There are some interesting algorithms,
like the NetClus algorithm.
Uncertain data,
means the data may contain noise,
may have approximate values,
or multiple possible values.
Usually we need to incorporate
some probabilistic information,
like distribution, or
approximate values that were
improve the quality of clustering.
Finally, recently,
there are lots of discussion on big data.
That means, we can model systems.
That may store and process very big data,
like weblog analysis.
Usually, like Google's MapReduce
framework is you have Map
function to distribute
the computation across many machines.
Then we have Reduce function to aggregate
the results obtained from the Map step.
So we can see, the data is very
rich that's why the clustering
is a rather sophisticated methodologies,
trying to handle different kinds of data.
[MUSIC]