[SOUND] Now we examine
another interesting line
of pattern discovery applications.
There's pattern discovery for
software bug mining.
We use software all the time.
But we also know software
may contain bugs.
But software usually could be quite big,
quite long, and
its running data could be even larger and
more complex.
So automatic debugging,
finding software bugs,
it's a very challenging
issue because often,
there's no clear specification or
property we can rely on.
We have to invest substantial human
effort first to analyze data,
analyze the source code, and analyze bugs.
So, if we can have certain
automated tool to do software
reliability analysis to find bugs,
it will save a lot of people's effort.
So for bug detection, there is one
category called static bug detection,
that means you check the source code and
try to find bugs.
Another code dynamic bug detection or
testing is you run the code,
you try to detect where could be the bugs.
The debugging usually is
you give me symptoms or
failures, I try to pinpoint
the bug locations in the code.
If we can do good pattern mining because
the code are running sequences that
may contain some hidden patterns.
If we can do pattern mining,
we will be able to find some common
patterns and some anomalies.
Usually the common patterns likely
are specifications or properties,
but the violations are anomalies comparing
to the common patterns, likely bugs.
So if we can do pattern mining,
we mine the patterns, it may narrow
down the scope of inspection.
For example, usually the code locations or
predicates that happen
more in the failing runs.
That means every time it fails, it likely
sees somewhere you can see it happens more
for certain predicates or happens more for
code locations, this kind of patterns.
But it happens less in the passing runs.
And likely, those code locations or
predicates are suspicious bug locations.
That may narrow down the scope for
the bug inspection.
So the typical software bug detection
methods contain their mining one,
could be mining rules from source code,
or may find deviant behavior.
Those are bugs by a statistic analysis,
you may find some source coded
substantially deviate from the others,
or you may mine some programming rules.
For example,
you first do a variable value assignment,
then you do the condition testing.
So if you use frequent itemset mining,
you may be able to identify those
typical program practice or rules.
Or you also can mine function
precedence protocols.
Simply says, if you find some functions
always precede some other functions,
so you can use frequent subsequence
mining to find such patterns.
And also, you may reveal
neglected conditions you base
on the different condition whether
it would be tested or never touched.
You use frequent itemset or
subgraph mining,
you'll be able to find such patterns.
Another interesting practice is
mining rules from revision histories.
You'll look at sequence of
the program coded revisions.
You'll use frequent itemset pack mining.
You may find certain general practice or
certain anomalies.
Actually we are going to
focus on one interesting bug.
We study, try to find copy and paste bugs.
So we try to mine copy-paste
patterns from the source code,
then we try to find the copy-paste bugs.
This one actually was one interesting
piece of work published in 2004,
called CP-Miner by YY Zhou's group.
And we are going to just show this,
this interesting
idea how to extend pattern mining
to find copy and paste bugs.
So copy and paste bugs is very common.
For example,
some statistics show they are 12%
of the code in Linux file system
are copy and paste code, and
19% of the code in X Window system,
also copy and paste.
But a copy and paste may introduce errors.
For example, the typical one
called forget-to-change bugs,
that means something like this code, okay.
If you see the first part,
the upper part, the for loop, okay,
this part and the down part,
another for loop, these two actually,
if you see many other things are just
the same, but there are something changed.
So you likely, this part,
the second part, was copy and paste from
the first part, and then do some changes.
But the problem is when
you do global change,
sometimes the programmer may forget
to change something like here, okay.
It means all the total in the front has
changed to taken, but the last total and
the second occurrence in this
statement forget to change to taken.
So this is a very common practice because
the carelessness of some programmer.
But how can we find this kind of bug,
actually this bug has really
happened in Linux 2.6.6?
Okay, then we will see how to
automatically find such bugs.
The general sequence,
the general way to solve this
problem we will be detail later.
As we may build a sequence
database from the source code,
mining such sequential patterns.
Then when we find some mismatched ID
names, then the bugs as well, okay.
This one was done by YY Zhou's
group that time she was at USC,
so it's very interesting
study using pattern mining.
So we first see how to build
sequence database from source code.
So the general philosophy is for
each statement,
we may match the statement into a number.
But how we can match the number,
for example, this two are 16,
the other two are also 16,
how we can find such similar sequences.
So the methodology is we
tokenize each component,
like just give you an example,
like old is assigned to 3.
And the variable new
is also assigned to 3.
How we can?
We based it for
different operators, constants,
or key words,
remain mapping to different tokens.
But for same type of IDs,
we map to the same token.
For example, old and new are both same
type of ID, these are both old new.
We do not care they are different IDs,
we just map them into the same token 5.
But it's assigned to, these two map to 61.
Then the value like 3 we map
into another token like 20.
Then these two statements, if we take the
same sequence, we give them a hash value.
These two statements should have
the same hash value, simply say,
these are very similar statements.
So if we do this,
either you'll see this total[i].adr and
the other one is total[i].bytes,
they essentially map to the same thing,
they got the same sequence.
So, then a program is mapped to
a long sequence, we can further
cut the long sequence by blocks.
For example, we can find at least,
fragments of the program
is matched to a sequence
in the same block,
you probably can see this is
the map into sequence database.
Then we can do sequential pattern
mining to detect forget-to-change bugs.
How to do sequential pattern mining?
Remember the previous
sequential pattern mining
allow arbitrary number
of gaps in the middle.
This is derived from
the customer shopping sequences.
But, for programming, for
finding a sequence in the copy and
paste bugs, you want to have exactly
one because you allow people
to insert some programming
statements right in the middle,
you count these as same kind of sequences.
But you don't want them to insert
too many statements in the middle,
because they likely they could
be complete different things.
So we can constrain the maximum gap,
like the small number of
statements in the middle.
Then we will still say these two sequence
of the code are the same
sequential pattern, okay.
Then we can compose larger copy and
paste segments because they
have many things in common.
We can combine the neighbor copy and
paste segments repeatedly.
Then we may try to find conflicts.
Essentially, we try to identify
those names that cannot be mapped to
the corresponding ones.
For example, if you see here,
you may see the concrete identifier,
F mapped to F1, this F also mapped to F1.
But the other F is mapped to F2,
so there's a conflict.
So we try to calculate the ratio.
Suppose if we find a 1 out
of 4 total is unchanged, so
the unchanged ratio is only 0.25.
If you set an unchanged ratio,
if it's greater than 0,
it means something did change.
But unchanged ratio is less
than specified threshold,
then we can say this likely could
be a copy and paste bug, okay.
So this one actually was
done by YY Zhou's group.
They work at CP-Miner.
They mined the common source code,
like Linux, Apache, Postgres.
So they actually got to find many copy and
paste bugs out of millions
of lines of code.
And you probably can see this sequential
pattern mining is very efficient.
That means that within a short time,
you can browse through millions lines of
code, finding such copy and paste bugs.
And based on their human identification,
these are the real bugs.
So it's very interesting
to see this pattern
mining can help finding software bugs.
[MUSIC]