[SOUND] Now, we come down to compare
these null invariant measures.
So, which one is better?
We know, we can sense not all those
null-invariant measures are created
equal so, we want to see which
one's better in all the cases.
Let's examine the two
variable contingency table of
the transactions containing milk and
coffee.
Let's look at the case in this data set.
So the first, you look at D1 and
D2, D1 and D2,
you probably can see the difference is
only on the number of null transactions.
But you also can see very likely, milk and
coffee should get together,
they should be positive.
In that sense,
you can see all of those five,
null-invariant measures,
they give equal value.
In this sense, no matter how many
transactions on the null part.
Okay, they do not change their value.
And also they are very close to one,
in the sense,
these are possibly getting together.
When you look at D3,
D3 means mc getting together is quite
rare because they get along more frequent.
In that sense,
all their values are very close to zero.
Then you look at the D4,
D4 says mc getting together or mc alone,
they are all like 1,000 and
1,000 and 1,000 cases.
No matter how many null transactions,
they actually got things right
in the middle this 0.5, 0.5.
Only Jaccard's 0.33,
actually just in Jaccard,
this one means its balance
is right in the middle.
Then we look at cases,
it could be D5 and D6.
D5, if you see this is 1,110 solved cases.
So what you probably can see,
is from coffee point of view,
like a coffee guy may say,
mc are likely getting together,
because they get along as 100
cases buying coffee but not milk.
1000 cases we're buying both coffee and
milk.
But for milk guy, they probably say,
they are very unlikely getting together,
because I got 10,000 cases buying milk but
not coffee.
But only 1000 case buying milk and coffee.
So, in that case you look
at different measures.
It's interesting to see,
All Confidence and
Jaccard they also say it's closer to zero,
unlikely getting together.
But Max Confidence says it's close to one,
they are very likely getting together.
Then we look at a Kulczynski said,
I'm right in the middle,
because the tug of the war
on each side is ten to one.
Then Cosine said, I'm a little
prone to unlikely getting together.
Now, we change this one even more.
This is 1,000 to ten, or 1,000 to 100,000.
The coffee guys said they are very,
very likely getting together.
But the milk guy said,
they are very unlikely getting together.
Now in this case,
you probably can see All Confidence and
Jaccard drop down to 0.01, and
even cosine dropped down to 0.1.
But if Max Confidence says, I am very
confident they are very close to one,
because they are very
likely getting together.
But in Kulcyzynski said, I'm still in
the neutral because this is 100 to one,
the other is one to 100,
they have the equal ratio.
So, which one do you like?
So, probably we can see D4 to D6.
The real case is, that differentiate
that five null-invariant measures.
But we probably can see,
Kulcyzynski measure
holds firm when in these
very imbalanced cases.
But the ratio is balanced on both sides,
and it holds firm at 0.5.
That looks interesting.
But on the other hand, we also know
those cases, some are very imbalanced,
we may want to introduce another
measure called imbalance ratio.
The imbalanced ratio is
introduced in the sense,
the support of item set A and
support of item set B,
their differences play important role
in this imbalance ratio computation.
Then you proceed for
the same cases in the last three,
the Kulcyzynski vector holds firms at 0.5.
But the imbalance ratio, okay,
D sub four cases is zero,
because they are already balanced.
And D sub five cases become 0.89,
they are rather imbalanced.
And D sub six cases,
it is very imbalanced.
So imbalance ratio, really can show
you how balanced the two sides are.
So we feel Kulcyzynski plus imbalance
ratio, these two things getting together
will present a clear picture for
all the three data sets, D4 through D6.
Because D4 is neutral and
balanced, D5 is neutral but
imbalanced, and D6 is neutral but
very imbalanced.
Finally, we're going to show you some
real data sets like a DBLP data sets,
we want to look at
co-author relationships.
So, let's look at this table.
This table we got around year 2007.
We study the recent database conferences,
we look at those authors,
they publish papers and they co-author
papers in database conferences.
But you can probably see,
the interesting thing is, for
example you look at Hans-Peter Kreigel and
Martin Pfeifle.
Martin Pfeifle got 18 papers, but all of
them are with with Hans-Peter Kriegel.
The Hans-Peter Krieger got 146 papers,
18 was with Martin Pfeifle.
Well, okay, you can see in that cases
Kulcyzynski shows pretty strong value that
simply says, these two authors
are closely tied together in some way.
But they are imbalanced as well.
We can see the case of imbalanced ratio,
you can either calculate
the imbalance ratio is really high.
So in that case,
you probably can easily judge Hans-Peter,
Kriegel likely to be
the adviser of Martin Pfeifle.
So using Kulcyzynski and imbalance ratio,
we can easily see advisor-advisee
relationships, and close collaborators.
In one research paper on
finding advisor-advisees,
we are really using those measures to
find them with reasonably high accuracy.
So finally,
we will show you a bunch of papers.
These are the papers quite representative
on how to judge the correlation
relationship, the different measures,
including their interest in measure,
the non-variant ones and the measure
we discussed on the Kulcyzynski.
Thank you.
[MUSIC]