Hi, my name is Sun lee Jong.
I'm a kitchen assistant
of this Coursera course.
Today, I'm going to introduce, how to
use an online cresting tool to apply and
to visualize the DBSCAN algorithm
from the real data set.
DBSCAN algorithm is introduced
in test the base algorithm.
If you're not familiar with the technical
details you may want to review the slides.
The data site that we're using today
is a Yelp restaurant data site.
It contains locations of a hundred
restaurants in Waterloo, Canada.
Each location is represented
by its longitude and latitude.
And we find this data
set in course material.
To start with,
we upload a data set file to the website,
select the given data set file and
then click on Start button.
The website is going to have
it automatically uploaded.
Then, make sure we're clustering by rows,
instead of clustering by columns.
Because each row here actually
represents a location.
Now, we choose a classroom
method to the DBSCAN and
insert the parameter value for epsilon.
Epsilon is the parameter in DBSCAN
algorithm, defines the neighborhood.
Here, we choose epsilon to be 0.005.
Click on Submit.
Here is a visualization of
the clustering results.
Because we are running the algorithm
on a two dimensional dataset.
We only need to look at this
very first visualization figure.
Each card represents a certain cluster.
And one of our cluster actually
represents the others.
As you can see from this visualization,
one of the most important characteristics
of the DBSCAN algorithm, is that they can
generate clusters of arbitrary shape,
in self clusters of just.
So I want to try different
parameter settings
to see how the classroom
result is different.
And I also want to try the classroom
algorithms different view of datasets.
If you're interested about exploring
more about DBSCAN algorithms,
here are some interesting open
questions about the algorithm.
Thank you.
[SOUND]
[MUSIC]