[SOUND]
Hi,
let's introduce the very
famous Apriori Algorithm.
This algorithm is the first
candidate generation and
test approach for frequent pattern mining.
It is a level-wise candidate
generation test approach.
Initially, the first time you just
scan the database once to get
frequent 1-itemset.
Then taking this frequent 1-itemsets,
you are going to generate
lens two candidate itemsets.
In the case iteration,
you're going to take a length-k frequent
itemsets to generate landscape
plus one candidate itemset.
Then you go against the database to
test these candidates generated,
and to find the real
frequent k+1 itemsets.
Every iteration you set k to k+1,
so you can go and
tier the no frequent itemsets
will be generate, or
no candidate itemsets can be generated.
Then after you exit from loop,
you just return all the frequent
itemsets derived, that's the algorithm.
Let's look at the pseudo-code.
We set C sub k to be
candidate itemset of size k,
F sub k to be frequent itemset of size k.
Initially, we just get
a frequent 1-itemsets.
Then we get into the loop.
Suppose the frequent k itemset
is not empty, then we get in.
We use ks frequent itemset to
generate k+1's candidate itemsets.
Then we go against the database
using the minimum support
to see which k+1 candidate itemset or
frequent.
We derive the frequent k+1 itemsets.
Then we reset k to k+1, and
here we get out of this loop.
We just return all the frequent k
itemsets for all the ks derived.
Let's look at the concrete example.
You look at this transaction database.
It contains only four transactions.
The first scan, you just try to find
their support for every single itemset.
Then we find d, the support is only one,
so it's not a frequent.
So then we just remove it, we get
a frequent 1-itemsets and their support.
Then we use this to derive
the candidate 2-itemsets, C sub 2.
Then we scan the database again,
we find the real support count.
Then we find these two blue
marker lines are infrequent,
we derive frequent 2-itemsets.
Then using frequent 2-itemsets, we derive
the frequent three candidate itemsets.
Remember, this one you
probably can't see a big cut.
Why?
Because you probably see A,
C, B, C are frequent,
you may think maybe A, B,
C could be candidate itemset.
But A, B is not frequent here,
so A, B, C will not be derived.
So we only derive B, C, E.
With another scan, we find it's support
is two, so it's frequent as well.
Then we find all the frequent one,
two, three itemsets.
The concrete implementation actually
involve self-joining and the pruning.
Self-joining goes like this.
We get abc, abd,
the first two are the same.
The third one is different, so
we generate this self-join,
generate this candidate set.
A similar thing we get acd, ace,
the first two are just the same.
The third one we get them together,
we get this candidate sets.
But we may need a pruning process.
The pruning is pretty simple.
Before you count against a database,
you proceed for
abcd, this bcd is there.
So this is a candidate one.
But for acde,
cde is not in the frequent three itemset.
So acd can not be the candidate,
so it's pruned.
So that's the simple way,
you bring in the self-joining and
pruning, we can solve this problem.
You'll find out we get only
one candidate sets, abcd.
Let's look at the SQL implementation of
this candidate set generation and test.
So we proceed the candidate
generation essentially this.
You proceed the self-joining.
How to do self-joining?
You'll see the first k-2.
They are all identical.
Then the last one, k-1 item.
One is smaller than the other.
We get one candidate set.
Then for this candidate set,
we still need the pruning.
The pruning essentially is
a check whether these subsets,
the k-1 subset containing this one.
If s is not in F k-1,
then we just delete this
candidate from the candidate set C sub k.
So this is a candidate generation.
The key step of SQL
implementation of Apriori.
[MUSIC]