[MUSIC]
Since the proposal of
the famous Apriori algorithm,
there have been many interesting
extensions or improvements in this method.
Let's just examine some of them.
So the first line of work is how
to reduce the number of passes
of transaction database scans.
We know that database scanning
involve disk accessing which
could be quite expensive.
But if you want to find
size 10 frequent item sets.
Likely, you will have to scan
this database ten times.
That's quite expensive.
To reduce a number of scans, so
there's several publications.
One is called partitioning method,
we're going to introduce.
Another one called dynamic
itemset counting method.
You will probably notice the first author,
Serge Brin who was a PC student
of Stanford university.
The second year, 1998 he actually proposed
one of the most famous algorithm
PageRank and set up a Google company.
Okay.
So this another line of the work is how
to shrink the number of candidates.
You will generate very large number
of candidate sets in many cases.
How to shrink the number of candidate sets
to be generated could be a big saving.
Hashing method is interesting one for
mining max patterns.
Bayardo also proposed pruning
by support lower bounding.
Another interesting method is
Toivonen proposed sampling method.
The third item's work is to explore
some special data structures.
Some tree projection method
using H-tree to do H-miner.
And hypercube decomposition is
another interesting method.
We're going to introduce a new
tree structure called FP-tree.
Let's look at the first one,
partitioning method.
Partitioning method guarantee
you only need to scan data twice
before you generate all the frequent item
sets no matter for how many case that is.
So they observed a very
interesting property called
any itemset potentially frequent
in transaction database
must be frequent in at least
one of its partitions.
That means suppose you get
a big transaction database,
you partition them into k partitions.
If items at X is not frequenting
any one of these k partitions,
it cannot be frequent in this
global transaction database.
Why?
Before you can see, if you got items at x
which is not frequent in the first one.
Not frequent in the second one.
Even not frequent in the case one.
So you add them together.
You add all these support together,
you get a global support.
You add all these database together,
you get a global database.
You frequently can see if every one
is smaller then sigma more times its
size then the finally the global
hour also smaller than 6,
sigma times the size of global database.
That's why at least one of this
database contain TDB frequent.
So with this operation, you can see this
partition method will need only two scans.
The first scan is you partition
database into K partition database.
How do you partition them?
Each partition you want them
to fit into the main memory.
Why?
Because no matter how you scan them,
you will not involve any database I/Os.
So that's a reason you can scan once
you put them the database, you can work
on it to derive k frequent items that for
no matter for how many case you can get.
Okay, that means you can derive
all the local frequent item sets.
Okay.
Then based on this property you
can do the second scan like this.
You can say,
since any frequent item set in
one of these k transactions
can be potentially frequent.
So the global candidate sets
is which is frequenting
any one of them,
it will be a global candidate item set.
Then, the second scan, just count
against each database kind of those
counts of the global candidate sets.
Then you will get their account,
you add them together,
you will be able to derive
global frequent patterns.
That's why this method is guaranteed
to scan the database only twice.
So this is pretty interesting.
Another method I'm going to introduce to
you called Direct Hashing and Pruning.
This method is trying to reduce
a number of candidate sets
based on hashing and pruning techniques.
The general philosophy can be like this,
okay.
The observation is, if the k-itemset is
frequent, then in this hashing bucket,
it contains several potential
itemsets that must be frequent.
So if the hash count is not frequent,
than any one of them cannot be frequent.
The general philosophy like this.
Okay.
Why are you going to derive
the frequent one item?
In the mean time you set
of the hash entry for
the potential two itemsets but
why you set a hash entry rather than count
each one because there could be many,
many distinct items.
So the frequent tool items as before,
you get a frequent 1,
the candidate 2 could be really,
really big.
But if you set a hash entry
to get several items,
share 1 hash entry,
the whole hash table will not be too big.
Then the interesting thing is,
while you derive frequent one itemset,
you also can cut many two itemsets
that can not be frequent.
For example suppose our
minimum support count is 70.
Then this one has only 35,
this one has only 58.
That implies those items,
none of those items can be frequent.
Because they share this entry,
their support count is
still below the threshold.
So only the second one, this bd,
be, de, the support is quite big.
The past support threshold,
these could be poked.
This may contain the real candidates sets.
Okay.
That's a reading you can
reduce the number of
candidates substantially using
this hashing and pruning method.
[MUSIC]