[SOUND]
Now
we are going to look at another
interesting pattern mining method.
It's Mining Frequent Patters by
Exploring Vertical Data Format.
This method is called ECLAT, or
equivalence class transformation method,
which in our philosophy looked like this,
okay?
In original transaction database,
it's horizontal data format in
the sense you get every row
you get transaction IDs and
a set of items in this item entry.
Then you can transform this
horizontal data format
into vertical data format like this.
For every item, a,
you will see which transaction IDs
is associated with this item a.
That means a bot, you reach transactions.
What's the benefit of this?
The first thing is,
you transform the Itemset into TidList.
The total size is approximately
the same if every entry or
every ID,
they have the similar number of bytes, but
the way to compute this will be
different with this TidList.
For example,
if you say what is TidList of e?
You get 10, 20, and 30.
What is TidList of a?
You get a 10 and 20.
Then how to derive ae?
You just intersect them together, you can
see you intersect this set with this set,
intersect two TidList, you derive
the TidList of this ae, this Itemset.
If this one contains sufficient
number of transactions,
then this is frequent like two,
then ae or be frequent.
If this one's infrequent,
then you don't need ae to go further,
that's a similar thing
as Apriori principle.
Then the properties of TidLists
basically say if these two TidList
is equivalent, that means they
have the same set of transactions.
If this one is the subset of the other
one, that simply says the transaction
containing X must always containing Y,
because this one is this one's subset.
So you probably can see,
if we try to derive frequent patterns
based on these vertical intersection,
we just need to see the size
of these transaction list.
But there's one interesting method
called diffset to accelerate the mining.
The reason is, when you get very
large number of transactions,
each item may be associated
with a very long TidList.
Then,their intersection,
like this e and the ce,
their intersection could be small,
but their difference could be small.
So you look at the intersection,
it's large, the difference could be small.
For example, you intersect these two,
the intersection is 10 and 20.
But the difference is only one.
So you only keep this,
you don't have to keep t(ce).
That may save a lot of space, okay?
This is the general idea.
Using diffset you can further
improve this efficiency.
[MUSIC]