[SOUND]
Hi, I'm going to introduce you another
interesting pattern mining approach
called pattern growth approach.
This approach is represented by
interesting algorithm called FPGrowth.
Let's look at how this algorithm works.
The general idea is first we find
the frequent single items and
then we partition the database
based on each such item.
Then we recursively grow frequent patterns
by doing the above iteratively or
recursively for each partitioned database,
also called conditional database.
To facilitate efficient processing, we
use a new data structure called FP-tree.
The whole mining can be
summarized as follows.
We recursively construct and
a mine conditional FP-trees.
Until the result FP-tree is empty or
until it contains only one path,
the single path will generate
all the combinations of its sub-paths
each of which is a frequent pattern.
Let's look at a simple example.
For this transaction database,
it has only five transactions.
Each contains a set of items.
So we can scan the database once.
Find the single of item frequent
pattern like the following.
Suppose minimum support is three.
We will be able to find
the following frequent single item.
Then we can sort the frequent
items based on it's
support frequency in
descending order like this.
Base on this, we can construct a tree by
first construct the header, following this
order, then scan the database,
we can construct this tree as follows.
For example, okay, if you look at
the first transaction, it's f, c,
a, m, p, so we construct it f, c,
a, m, p with only support as 1.
Then we get f, c, a, b, m,
we constructed this f, c, a, b, m.
And this power support becomes 2,
this maintains to be 1.
You can go one by one working
on the following tree.
Then to mine this tree, we can use the
divide and conquer and do it recursively.
We can do it like this, okay, for each
tree we can construct this pattern base.
We call it p's conditional pattern base,
m's conditional pattern base.
Let's look at how p's conditional
pattern base is constructed.
So if you can see,
p is the leaf of the node.
You only look up.
You get f, c, a, m that supports 2 because
p occurs together with
this branch only twice.
That's why you get f, c, a, m 2.
Then for the same reason,
you look at the other p,
it's cb happens only once together with p,
that's why we get cb1, okay.
Then if you want to look at
m's conditional database,
the philosophy you were thinking
the patterns having m but not having
p because of p already being taken care
of by the p's conditional pattern base.
So you look at m's conditional database,
actually you also look up and
you get f, c, a, so for this branch they
occur twice, that's why you get f, c, a 2.
For the same reason, you look at
this m and you get an f, c, a, b 1.
So you get f, c, a, b 1.
You can do this on and on.
And with this, you can get
into transform the prefix paths
of p to get the following.
Then, the remaining task which is,
mind this, conditional pattern base.
For this conditional pattern base,
we mine single item patterns,
we construct the FP-tree and
mine it recursively.
For example, for p's conditional
pattern base, you will get only c: 3,
the reason is f, a, m,
and b they never occur
more than three times, so they are out,
they are not frequent so you only get 3.
But for m-conditional pattern-base,
you per can see f, c, a really
occurs three times, the b only occurred
once, then you'll get a f, c, a 3.
And b-conditional pattern-base gives
you where you can see none of them,
actually pass the support threshold of 3,
so it's empty.
So let's just look at of course,
you'll get a and
c's pattern-base like f: 3 and fc:3.
Actually for the single branch, you can
dump all the possible combinations there,
support our tree.
But we just look in the recursive way
how we can mine this pattern-base.
For this pattern-base,
you probably can see, you can say for
a's conditional pattern-base
you'll get this.
You'll get fc: 3, and for c you get f: 3,
you can see that's the same thing.
Then for this particular am
conditional FP-tree you might,
you just take a c,
you say c's that means a, m, c or c, a,
m their conditional pattern-base
is only f: 3, you get this.
Then you can dump all
the patterns like this.
For single branch essentially that's
the same thing, you will dump
all the patterns, like all the possible
combinations, they are all three, okay.
You can see if you get
a single prefix-path,
you actually can partition this into two
parts like this path you can mine it,
and this path you can mine it and then you
can just concatenate the path and results.
What about if tree cannot
fit in the main memory?
If you cannot fit in the memory,
we can use database projection.
That means, we project the database
based on the patterns,
based on single items set, okay.
So, then we can construct and mine
this tree for each projected database.
So we can have parallel projection or
partition projection,
two different methods.
The parallel projection means for
this one,
you will get f4 predict database and
f3 predict database.
For example, for
this first stream you will see gh
suppose is non frequent to only f.
F's a frequent.
You will get an f4 predict database,
you'll get an f2, f3.
Okay, then, f3's predicted base,
you get f2.
That's one,
and every one of these projected
databases is independent of the others.
So, you can mine them in parallel.
But then,
you also can have partition projection.
Partition projection the general
philosophy is for each string.
You only put into one place.
For example, this one country is
therefore you only put f2, f3,
but you don't put this f2
to f3 projected database.
When you're finished mine this f4,
when you do this projection then you
think this one migrates to f3,
you put this one into f3, okay.
So that's just a different choices for
different partition of
parallel projections,
it's just a different way of implemented,
thank you.
[MUSIC]