In the last session of this lecture,
we are going to introduce
probabilistic hierarchical clustering.
What is probabilistic
hierarchical clustering?
Let's first examine the problems of
algorithmic hierarchical clustering.
The first problem for
algorithmic hierarchical clustering is it
is nontrivial to choose
a good distance measure.
For example,
we already see the single link,
the complete link,
the average link and the central link.
They're all different measures, but
it's hard to choose a good distance
measure based on the application problems.
The second problem is it is hard to
handle missing attribute values because
when the attribute value is missing, it
may impact on the quality of clustering.
The third one is the optimization goal of
algorithmic hierarchical clustering is
not so clear because it is a heuristic
algorithm, it more relies on local search.
Now, there is another approach called
probabilistic hierarchical clustering.
This method essentially uses
probabilistic models to measure
distance between clusters.
It is largely a generative
model which means it
regards the set of data objects
to be clustered as a sample
of the underlying data generation
mechanism to be analyzed.
And then you finally find the parameter,
find out how they generate this data set.
It is easy to understand.
[COUGH] It has the same efficiency as
algorithmic agglomerative clustering
method and, also,
it can handle partially observed data.
In practice, we can assume the generative
models adopt common
distribution functions.
For example, we can assume it's
a Gaussian distribution or
Bernoulli distribution, and
governed by a set of parameters.
Let's look at the generative model.
In the generative model, we can assume,
given a set of one-dimensional points,
X, we can assume they are generated
by a Gaussian distribution like this.
That means you're essentially
using different mu and sigma.
You may generate the distribution
according to the typical,
normal distribution or
Gaussian distributing formula.
Then, the probability a single point,
x sub i, which is
one point in the set of X,
is generated by the model.
Essentially, it's what's
the probability to generate
x sub i under the condition of mu and
sigma is based on this formula.
Then for the likelihood that
this whole set of X generated,
essentially, is the likelihood for
the normal distribution to
generate this set of x points.
Essentially, it's the probability
of a set of points, x,
under the condition of mu and
sigma squared.
For i from 1 to N,
all of these probability multiplying
together we get the probability
generated at the data set, x.
Then the task of learning this
generative model, essentially,
we try to find the parameters,
a mu and a sigma.
So for this particular distribution,
we try to find the maximum
likelihood this set of x has
generated, according to
these two parameters.
So the Gaussian distribution usually,
I think most people know, for
example, for a bean machine,
if you drop a ball with pins,
if you use many, many balls,
finally you will find the distribution
is a Gaussian distribution.
Then if we have may points,
we can assume these points are actually
generated by the Gaussian
distribution like this.
Actually, for a one-dimensional Gaussian,
this different mu, different in mean and
different of variance,
you probably can see that it
generate different distribution.
For a two-dimensional Gaussian,
an image generated in 3-D space,
you probably can clearly see
the distribution of this 2-D Gaussian.
Then a probabilistic hierarchical
clustering algorithm,
essentially, is suppose
we regard the partition,
the whole set of points,
into m clusters, C sub one to C sub m.
Then the quality of the clustering
can be measured using this quality
function that's the product
of all those probabilities.
Then if we want to merge two clusters,
C sub j1 and
C sub j2, then the change in
quality of the overall clustering
is one criterion.
So you probably can see this is the merged
cluster, your generating new cluster,
and this originally two cluster disappear
from the original set of clusters.
So that's the new clustering, that's the
original clustering, because if you merge
this, essentially, the sum of
the square arrows will be increasing.
So that's the reason you're trying
to minimize that increasing.
That's the probability of P(C sub i).
Now, you get the probability of
these two merged together, okay.
The you have to minus the original
probability, i from 1 to m.
Then the distance between clusters C1 and
C2 is, this is the probability of C1 and
C2 together as one cluster,
these are the independent clusters.
If this distance is less than zero,
we should merge these two clusters.
So that's the idea, or the essence,
of the probabilistic hierarchical
clustering algorithm.
[MUSIC]