[SOUND]
So
first, we will introduce basic
concepts of partitioning algorithms.
The partitioning method is essentially
to discover the groupings in the data.
That means you get K groups if you want to
partition, I mean, 2K groups by optimizing
a specific object function, for
example, sum of the square distance.
And then we iteratively improve
the quality of such partitioning.
So the K-partitioning method,
we partition a dataset D of n
objects into a set of K clusters.
Then we definitely can
iteratively improve it, so
that an object function is optimized,
for example,
the object function could be the sum
of the square distance is minimized,
where C sub k is the centroid or
medoid of cluster capital C sub k.
So a typical objective function is Sum of
Squared Errors is often written as SSE.
So a clustering, okay, for the SSE,
is sum of K clusters,
k is from 1 to K, okay.
Then for each such cluster if
an object's i is in this cluster,
then the square error that simply says
the distance of sum of these squares.
These such distance, the whole function,
is a K clusters, and
each cluster get its points to its
center the sum of such a square,
distance or square errors.
We want to minimize this
objective function.
Then in general what we can think,
conceptual we can think of this,
if you get a very nice K cluster, then,
all the objects to the center
is somehow shorter, okay.
It is shorter than the sum of the square
distance or the square errors.
Actually, it will be pretty small.
That's why we can't get
within the cluster center,
the sum of the square
error is pretty small.
Then if we get a K such thing, we add them
together, the whole thing will be smaller.
For the K-partitioning method, essentially
the problem is given a K, the number
of clusters, we want to find a partition
of these K clusters that optimize
the chosen partitioning criterion, for
example, the sum of square distance.
However, to find a global optimal,
actually we need to exhaustively
enumerate all partitioning because
the potential number of partitioning
actually is exponential.
So more realistically,
we should get a heuristic method,
that means the greedy algorithms.
For example, the typically used
like the K-Means, K-Medians,
K-Medoids and all the other methods
are all greedy algorithms or
heuristic methods to find
such a nice partition.
[MUSIC]