[SOUND]
As we just had discussed,
the quality of K-means clustering is quite
sensitive to the initial relation status.
Then we need to see how to
do good in initialization so
we find a good quality
clustering using K-means method.
I just gave you a simple
example everybody can see.
Different initializations may generate
rather different clustering results.
Some may not be optimal at all.
Just give you example,
suppose we have only four points,
we will find two clusters.
If we initialize in the solid circle.
That means these two points get into one
cluster like if we give you the center
like this two, they will attract these
two and these two as in one cluster.
Then actually it becomes stabilized,
because you calculate the center,
the center is still here.
They will not move.
So then you find a pretty ugly cluster,
because you perceive these,
if you vertically group
things into two clusters.
The sum of the square distance or
SSE actually become rather small.
From this point of view
we know the quality of
a clustering could be very
sensitive to the initialization.
More recently, MacQueen in 1967 said
we should select the k seeds randomly.
Now we need to run this algorithm
multiple times using different seeds.
In some software package,
they may even say,
run these algorithms 200 times.
Finally find which one you derive
the best K-Means cluster simply
says you want to find the SSE,
the sum of the square arrow is minimized.
There are many other methods also
proposed for better initialization.
For example, there's one called K-Means++,
proposed in 2007.
Essentially this ++
initialization is as follows.
The first centroid that you can select
randomly, but then the next centroid to be
selected, you try to find the farthest
point from the currently selected points.
That means a selection based
on weighted probability score
based on a different probability you
select which is best for the next one.
Then this selection continues until
all the k centroids are obtained.
That initialization is done.
Then we can run the K-Means algorithm.
I'll give you a simple
example of protein C,
poor initialization may lead
to some poor clustering.
For example we take the same data sets,
those black points as we've shown before,
now we give you two
same choice initialized as the red
lines here, the blue lines here.
With this initialization,
we can get clusters,
we can assign these objects into two
different clusters in different colors.
One, the upper part,
those parts assigned to the red cluster.
The lower part assigned
to the blue cluster.
Then we can recalculate the center again.
You can probably see
the center actually moved.
And with this recalculation we
can re-assign those points.
You can run this if you want.
You probably can see finally they're
stable like this, but actually,
this is not a very good cluster at all.
That means that this run of the K-Means
generates a poor quality clustering.
That is simply giving us a simple show.
We do need some smart interrelations or
multiple random initialization
is the best ones.
So this is the initialization
of K-Means clustering.
[MUSIC]