[MUSIC]
Now, I'm going to introduce you
another interesting K partitioning
clustering method called
the K-Medoids Clustering Method.
Why do we need to study
K-Medoids Clustering Method?
Just because the K-Means algorithm
is sensitive to outliers.
Because a mean is
sensitive to the outliers.
Just give you a simple example,
if you look at a company's salary,
if you adding another very high salary,
the average salary of the whole
company shifts quite a lot.
So, let's look at the K-Medoids,
what is K-Medoids?
That means instead of taking the mean
value of object in a cluster,
as our centroid,
we actually can use the most
centrally located object in the cluster or
we call medoids.
That means the K-Medoids clustering
algorithm can go in a similar way,
as we first select the K points as
initial representative objects,
that means initial K-Medoids.
The difference between K-Means is K-Means
can select the K virtual centroid.
But this one should be the K
representative of real objects.
Then we put this one into repeat loop.
We can assign, similarly,
we assign each point to the cluster
with the closest medoid.
Then, we can randomly select
a non-representative object,
suppose it's o sub i, or see whether we
use o sub i to replace one medoid, m.
Whether it will improve
the quality of the class ring,
that means the total cost
of swapping is negative.
Simply says, it was sloppy,
we can reduce some of the square arrows.
Then, we are going to swap m with object
oi to form the new set of medoids.
Then we need to redo the assignment.
And here, this process goes, and here,
the convergence criteria is satisfied.
Now, we'll see a small example how
a typical K-Medoids Algorithm is exacted.
We look at the PAM, as an example.
Suppose we are given ten small number
of points in this small graph.
In this 2D space,
we want to find the two clusters.
At the very beginning,
we arbitrarily choose k objects here.
We choose two objects as initial medoids.
Then we will find the clusters
of these medoids, as follows.
Okay.
Then, we will see whether we can randomly
choose another object like O random.
Say these non-medoic object.
We want to see whether it
could become a medoid.
If it would reduce the total cost.
Always say we get a better SSE.
And in this case,
suppose we choose one here, but
we found it does not really reduce any,
the total SSE.
Then we actually can get another one.
Like we get this orange one.
Then we look at the cluster we can form.
We know this one will
reduce the total SSE.
That simply said the quality
of the cluster is improved.
Then we will do the swapping.
So this essentially is
listed here as we initially,
we select initial K medoids randomly.
Then, we will do object reassignment.
Then we try to swap medoid,
m, with the random
non-medoid object, o sub i,
if it improves the clustering quality.
Then we'll do it again and again until
the convergence criterion is satisfied.
So this is just a simple
execution to illustrate the ideas
of this K-Medoids, how it is executing.
Now we see these K-Medoids clustering
essentially is try to find the k
representative objects, so
medoids in the clusters.
And, the typical arrow is in PAM,
called Partitioning Around the Medoids,
was developed in 1987 by
Kaufmann & Rousseeuw,
starting from initial sets of medoids.
Then we iteratively replace one of
the medoids by one of the non-medoids,
if such a swapping improve the total
sum of the squared errors.
That is the total quality of the cluster.
This method works effectively for
small data sets.
Because we can keep trying different
swapping, but it cannot scale well,
because the computational
complexity is quite high.
If we look at it into detail, actually,
this computational complexity for
every swapping, actually, it's to
the square of the number of points.
That's quite expensive.
So, how to improve its efficiency.
There's one proposal by same
authors in 1990 called CLARA.
Essentially, it's PAM on samples.
That means, instead of using the whole
points, we choose a sample, s.
S is the sample size.
Then, the computational complexity,
this square, actually,
comes down to the size of the sample.
However, if the sample,
initial sample selection, is no good,
the final classroom quality could be poor.
Then in 1994, there's another
algorithm called CLARANS proposed,
as every iteration we do
randomized re-sampling.
That means,
we do not keep exact the same sample.
We do randomized re-sampling, that, or
ensure the efficiency and
the quality of clustering.
[MUSIC]