[MUSIC]
In this session, I'm going to introduce
the K-median and the K-modes clustering
methods as two interesting alternatives
to the K-means clustering method.
Why we want to do K-Medians.
Because medians are better than
means when we encounter outliers.
Medians usually less sensitive
to outliers comparing to means.
For example, in a large firm, okay,
there could be many employees.
We want to find the median salary,
even when you're adding,
when you add a few top executives,
the mean salary may change quite a lot.
The median could still be very stable.
So that's the reason, instead of
computing the mean value of the object
in the cluster, so
we take the medians of the centroid.
And we use L1 norm.
That means the distance
as our distance measure.
The criterion function for the K-Medians
algorithm is written as this.
The center is sum, the total sum should
be K from one to the number of cluster K,
and for each cluster the object in the
cluster you just look at the difference.
The difference take the absolute value
of their distance to the median.
The K-Medians clustering algorithm
essentially is written as follows.
The first,
at the very beginning we selected
K points as the initial
representative objects.
That means as initial K medians.
Then we get into this loop, we assign
every point to its nearest median.
Then we re-compute the median using
the median of each individual feature.
Then this process repeats until
the convergence criterion is satisfied.
Then we look at k-modes as another
interesting alternative to k-means.
K-modes essentially is to
handle categorical data.
Because K-Means cannot handle
non-numerical, categorical, data.
Of course we can map
categorical value to 1 or 0.
However, this mapping cannot
generate the quality clusters for
high-dimensional data.
Then people propose K-Modes
method which is an extension
to K-Means by replacing the means
of the clusters with modes.
The Similarity measure
between object X and
the center of cluster Z is
written as follows, okay.
This is the similarity,
we can see distance measured,
distance function, okay.
For the jth field of object x,
that means x sub j, and
look at the jth field of the cluster
center z, what's a distance?
It essentially is if this object is not
equal to the center on the same attribute,
essentially say they are different,
then we just say the distance
is one because it's very dissimilar,
or the distance is largest.
However, when this value is equal
to this attribute center here
then we use this formula.
This formula actually means if
there are many many objects occur
the same in this cluster, okay.
Then, this value actual be very small.
For example if the attribute cluster,
there's only one value.
But if very frequent,
then this guy have to equal to this value.
Then, this division where it lead to one,
and the distance is smallest.
In most cases,
the more frequent for this j value,
and this one would be closer to one,
so the distance is smaller.
And if this one is very rare you
go to the very rare value and
the number of distinct value is quite big.
So this your distance is closer to l.
But this is a quite reasonable definition.
That means this dc measure, distance
function is essentially frequency-based.
The more frequented the closer
the last frequent and
there are far away evan it
may equal to this value.
The whole algorithm that were not list
here but is still based on the iterative
one we first will object cluster
assignment then to centroid
update then we take this one into loop and
tear the criterion reached.
Then there is another iterative
method called fuzzy K-Modes method.
The fuzzy K-Modes method essentially
is to calculate a fuzzy cluster
membership value for
each object to it's cluster.
Simply says,
you give a fuzzy cluster value,
if it's very close to this cluster,
the fuzzy value is closer to 1.
It's far away from this cluster, and the
fuzzy value is somewhat closer to zero.
Okay, and if we have the data some
attributes are categorical attributes,
some attributes are numerical attributes
we can use K-Prototype method essentially
for numerical one we can use a method
the function similar to the K-Means.
And the categorical one we
can use similar to K-Mode and
finally we integrate this,
we can get a K-Prototype method.
[MUSIC]