[SOUND] Hi, in the last session of this
lecture, we're going to introduce
Kernel K-Means Clustering method.
What is Kernel K-Means?
Essentially is we know K-Means
can only detect clusters that
are linearly separable, they will have
difficulty to handle non-convex clusters.
For example, if you look at this
set up data points if we say,
k equals 2 we want to find these
two clusters of different color.
For example, the red one is
a core part right in the center,
the blue one is a big ring
surrounding this circle.
However, for K-Means, you can only
find something linearly separable.
Likely, you will chop every cluster in two
half and you find something quite ugly.
Then our idea is if we can project
data onto a high-dimensional
kernel space and then perform
K-Means clustering on this space.
We may be able to solve this
problem of the clustering problem.
That means we'll remark data
plans in the input space
on to a high damage in our feature
space using the corner function.
Then we perform a K-means
on the map feature space.
Of course, by doing so their computation
or complexity could be higher.
Because we need to compute and
store n by n kernel matrix generated from
the kernel function on the original data.
If the original data contain n objects,
if this n is large,
then n by n kernel matrix
could be very large.
Actually the widely studied the spectral
clustering can be considered as
a variant of Kernel K-Means clustering,
that's this Kernel K-Means.
It's a pretty interesting.
Let's look at kernel functions and
Kernel K-Means clustering.
The typical Kernel functions, for example,
we may have polynomial kernel of degree h,
you use this formula.
If we have Gaussian radial basis function,
RBF, the RBF Kernel is
a typical Gaussian function.
Sigmoid kernel is defined in this way, and
the formula for
kernel matrix X that means for
any two points, Xi sub i and X sub j.
Within cluster C sub k then we can map
into this kernel function in this way
then if we want to compute
sum of the square errors.
Okay so a Kernel K-Means the formula
is as follows whether you can see is
we want to find the number
of clusters from one to K.
K is a number of clusters then from each
cluster, each point in cluster C sub K,
this part where we just need to use
some of the squared distance phi Xi,
and the cluster center C sub k.
Then the formula for the cluster
centroid is very similar to the K-means.
As we use C sub k, the center essentially
is defined by the sum of this function
divided by the size of this cluster.
The clustering can be performed even
without actual individual projection
of this one for the data points with what
we needed just computing those formulas.
Here I give you the Kernel function
to see how we can do the mapping.
Suppose we want to check how to map
the real points into this RBF corner.
Okay we are given five
original points like this.
X sub 1, X sub 2, X sub 3 to X sub 5.
For these five points
this is original space.
If we set sigma equals to 4
actually you can set sigma to
other values as well, okay.
Equals to 4, the calculation
just a little nicer and simpler.
So you probably can see then if we
want to calculate this distance,
okay, this formula, this formula
that is on the top of this part.
What we can see is x1 is zero zero, so
there are two zeroes, and x two,
x is four four, these two fours.
So when you compute this distance you
basically compute the sum of their square
distance, equals 32,
then based on these formulas or
we get a e to the power
minus 32 divide by 2.
Times 4 square, then you get to
without a e, to the power of minus 1.
Then you can see for this mapping suppose
sigma equals 4, what we can get is for
k is when i equals one, you'll get x1, x1.
You look at x1, x1 they're the same so
this part is essentially you derive
as zero okay because of this mapping.
Then if you get x1, x2,
what you can see here is you get
this value e to the power of -1.
Similarly you can derive other values.
What you see is originally
you have five points,once
you map to this RPF kernel
space we get a 5 by 5 matrix.
That's why the computation could
be more expensive because you
map into n by n matrix.
Now we want to calculation the Kernel
K-Means clustering using this example.
For this example what you can see is
these are the original data points
for this data set.
If we want to use K-Means to
generate the two clusters,
you will be able to generate like this.
This is pretty ugly,
because you can see this very
dense kernel will be split, and
this ring will be split as well.
You generate something really very ugly,
not like a quality cluster.
However, if we are to
Gaussian RBF Kernel transformation
mapped it into a Kernel Matrix K for
any two points.
Using this function and
the Gaussian Kernel, we'll be able
to generate pretty nice clusters.
That means the K-Means clustering actually
is conducted on a mapped data and
then we can generate the quality clusters.
That's why the Gaussian K-Means Clustering
could be rather powerful.
Here are a set of interesting references,
you want to look at it.
The first on is MacQueen's paper, Lloyd
paper as you can see is published in 1982.
Actually in 1957,
there was a Bell Lab papers collections,
essentially the material was first appear
in 1957 in Bell Lab internal report, okay.
Then the other interesting papers and
books you may like to read,
as well, thank you.
[MUSIC]