Now, we first introduced a few
previous phrase mining methods.
Phrase mining actually
originally came from
the natural language processing community
called chunking or noun phrase chunking.
Essentially is a remodel of phrase
as a sequence of labeling problem.
For example, you can squeeze a label word
at the beginning of this noun phrase,
then you see another word that could
be inside of noun phrases, and
you may have something
outside of this phrase.
This will need a lot of annotation and
a training effort.
For example, you may ask domain experts
to annotate hundreds of
documents as training data.
Then we can use the software, use
the measures to train a supervised model
based on part-of-speech features
like part of speech tracking.
Okay, the recent trend is
also try to use web n-grams.
Those web n-grams,we can
get some statistics,
we'll be able to use this distributional
features to generate good phrases.
This one was found by Bergsma and
others in 2010.
The state-of-the-art
performance using this approach
is about 95% accuracy and
about 88% phrase-level F-score.
However, this method suffers
from the high annotation cost.
And then it will not be scalable
to a new language for example,
new labor English, it may not be used for
French or a new domain like you
labor the news may not be able to use for
computer science or new genre, okay?
So it may not fit domain-specific,
dynamic, emerging applications.
For example, there are lots of new
articles in scientific domain,
computer science domain or
like medical domains.
Or the machine may generate
a lot of query logs.
Our social media may contain Yelp and
Twitter data.
This kind of data set is so
domain specific and dynamic,
so it's hard to assign or change every
subset of such data using annotation.
So people want to develop
unsupervised phrase mining method.
Actually, many unsupervised
phrase mining studies are close
linked to as topic modeling.
Topic modeling essentially is
a new recent developed method.
Represent topics by many,
many phrase words.
You get every topic is written by
a word distribution, and documents
a set of documents actually may contain
many topics with different proportions.
This method does not require any prior
annotations or labeling of the documents.
It relies on statistical
topic modeling algorithm.
One of the most popular ones, LDA, or
we call Latent Dirichlet Allocation
developed by David Blei and
others in 2003.
Actually to do phrase mining using
topic modelling there are three
different methods.
One is we simultaneously
infer the topics and
the tokens, the phrases at the same time
using some kind of generative model.
The second method is first
using generative model to
generate topic models and
using topic model, try to group
different words into n-grams,
into phrases to visualize such topics.
The third one, the newest developed
one is first we phrases mining
before we do topic model.
That means, we mine phrases and
impose such phrases
on the bag-of-words modelling process.
So let's look at the first method.
We call strategy 1 is simultaneously
inferring phrases and topics.
There studies the first one in 2006
was called bigram topic model.
That means we use some kind of
probabilistic generating model
to look at the previous words in
the topic to see whether the next word
should belong to the same
topic should be a phrase.
And it's generalization from this
Bigram Topic Model is TNG or
called Topical N-Grams model.
It was developed in 2007.
It is a probabilistic model.
Generates words in textual order,
then create n-grams by
concatenating successive bigrams.
Then the source that is by Lindsey and
others into some twelve
called PDLDA or Phrase-Discovering LDA.
For this measure, we first view each
sentence as a time-series of words.
Then using PDLDA, and
assume that generative parameter like
those topic may change periodically, then
each word is drawn based on the previous
m words, based on the previous context.
And the current phrase topic, so
we can generate whether this
word should be there or not.
Okay, this method, due to its high model
complexity, it tends to overfitting.
That means it overfitting
to a particular topic.
Sometimes it may not generate
very good quality phrases.
Another why it has high inference cost,
because of this complex generative
process, it runs pretty slow.
The second strategy is post
topic-modelling phrase construction.
That means refers topic modeling,
then we do phrase construction.
The first that work called TurboTopics.
TurboTopics was developed in 2009
by David Blei and John Lafferty.
The general idea is first to Latent
Dirichlet Allocation to do topic modeling,
then based on topic modeling we do
post-processing to construct the phrases.
Okay, that means we first perform LDA on
corpus to assign each token a topic model.
This is topic modelling.
Then, we'll merge adjacent unigrams
with the same topic model by
a distribution-free permutation test
on arbitrary-length back-off model.
For example, you can see this.
If you see phase, transition, and
you see phase transition
are in same topic number 11.
And they are consecutive,
likely they could form a phrase.
You can recursively merging
generating such phrases.
We will end recursive merging when all
significant adjacent unigrams have been
merged, so then you will be able
to generate some good phrases.
Another method called KERT is also
first do topic modelling
them do phrase construction.
It was developed by Marina Danilevsky and
others in 2014.
It take first do some LDA, and
then to post-processing for
phrase construction.
The first one the same is turbo topics,
then the interesting thing is it performs
frequent pattern mining to extract
candidate phrases within each topic.
Then perform phrase ranking,
based on four different criteria.
One criteria called popularity.
For example, if you see information
retrieval is more popular,
then cross-language information retrieval,
then information retrieval as a phrase
will rank higher than the cross-language
information retrieval.
The second criteria is concordance.
For example, if you see strong tea quite
often rather you see powerful tea,
or you see active learning quite often
rather than you see learning and
the classification getting together
as a sequence, then we will
say strong tea and
active learning is higher concordance.
The third one for informativeness
essentially is, whether the phrase
generator is more informative, it contains
retrieved information, discriminative.
For example, if you see this paper,
it's almost every research paper,
they have a lot of this paper, so
this paper is more like a stock
words here is more like a stock
phras,e it is not informative.
It rank low, like it should be removed.
The first criteria is completeness.
For example, you see vector machine,
almost every time you see this phrase,
you'll also see support vector machine.
That means vector machine
may not be complete,
and support vector machine
is a complete phase.
Then not only you can compare
phrase quality with the same lens,
in many cases you can compare
phrase quality of mixed lens.
That means you compare vector
machine vs support vector machine.
Rather than using the same lens,
you compare them.
With this process, frequent pattern
mining plus phrase ranking,
this message generate
better quality phrases.