Now we introduce an interesting
phrase mining method
called ToPMine which mines quality
phrases without training data.
This method actually belongs to
strategy three as we discussed.
We first do phrase mining,
then do topic modeling.
Why we want to do that way?
We can see if we use Strategy 2,
we first do
topic modelling, then try to do phrase
modeling, we may encounter some problems.
For example, let's look at this example.
Suppose we first do topic
modeling in this one.
But remember, the topic modeling you will
regenerate a larger number of topics.
Suppose knowledge discovery,
you see knowledge is in the red topic and
discovery is in the blue topic.
Okay.
The same thing as support vector machine,
you may get a support as in one topic
vector is another and the machine is
in the topic the same as support.
If that's the case, we'll never be able
to generate knowledge discovery also for
a vector machine is quality phrases
because they belong to different topics.
How can we fix this problem?
If we switch order between phrase
mining and topic modeling That means
we first two phrase mining if we can find
knowledge, discovery is a quality phrase.
A least a squares is
another quality phrase and
support vector machines
assert quality phrase.
Then, we will be able to generate
the very high quality topic models for
example knowledge discovery is one topic,
least a squares is another topic Support
vector machine is another topic.
Can we do that?
Okay, so the trick is we
can first do phrase mining.
Then we do document segmentation.
Then we do phrase ranking.
After that,
we take those phrase as constraints.
Then we do topic modeling inference
then we will be able to get
those high quality phrases and
high quality topic models.
Let's look at this method top mine method.
The method was developed
by Ahmed El-Kishky's and
his team, In publishing VLDB 2015.
At first do phrase mining then
do phrase-based topic modelling.
The phrase mining is first mine
frequent contiguous patterns
that only can extract these
candidate phrases and their counts.
This method is very much like a typical
frequent pattern mining methods.
Then we can agglomerative merging
those adjacent unigrams guided
by a significance score.
We are going to ensure you see all later,
okay?
Then we can do documents segmentation.
That means we will work out to the base
of raw frequency based going back
to the document to see which one we count
which we get rectified true frequency.
For example,
just give you a simple example,
suppose we have support
vector machine as a phrase.
It occurs 90 times.
Then vector machine,
as a phrase it occurs 95 times.
Support vector occurs even 100 times.
However you go back to the documents
you will find if you count support
vector machines it's a phrase.
You will not recount vector
machine as independent phrase or
support vectors, independent phrase.
Actually you'll decrease
their count substantially.
That the count is we call
the rectified frequency.
Analysis can be based on rectified
frequency instead of raw frequency.
Now we can rank those phrases
based on popularity, concordance,
informativeness and the completeness
as we just discussed in KERT.
After this we can do phrase
space topic modelling.
That means we can,
taking those mined bag of phrases.
We pass them PhraseLDA which
is the extension of LDA.
This method will constrains
all the words in a phrase.
So, each sharing the same latent topic.
In that way, we'll be able to
divide better quality topic models.
This matter essentially doing
collocation mining, then is,
we were to find a sequence of the words
that occur more frequently than expected,
then we would say they likely
should be a phrase, okay?
For example,
if you see "strong tea", okay?
You see it happens frequently together.
Then you look at a strong, how many times
happens tea, how many times it happens.
Then you see strong tea happen together
more frequently than expected frequency.
That means strong tea should be a phrase.
How can we measure such things?
We can measure this based
on different measures.
For example, the mutual information, okay.
And this essentially is
paralyzed mutual information.
And we can do t-test, can do z-test,
can do chi-squared test,
can do likelihood ratio,
actually using all the different
measures we can confirm,
the phrase would generate
a truly good phrases.
Usually use any of the good measures,
little work.
That means many of these
measure can be used to
guide the agglomerative
phrase segmentation.
Let's look at the example.
Suppose we have a bunch of documents,
one says Markov
blanket feature selection for support
vector machines and all the others.
How can we know without training to see
feature selection should be a phrase,
support vector machine should be a phrase,
Markov blanket should be a phrase.
Actually the trick is very simple,
if we think about the normal distribution,
the Gaussian distribution,
by basic statistics we know,
if you've got a Gaussian distribution,
you get a one standard deviation away.
Actually it's about the chance
to get this is one minus 68.2%.
But, you get three
standard deviations away.
The chance is very, very small.
It simply says you only got 0.3% of chance
to have three standard deviation away.
And then how do you explain it?
Likely they should get together,
as an exception, but
not as a random distribution.
They should be a phrase.
Okay.
We can use some significant score like
a church developing in
1991 right on this former.
This is very much in the same
spirit as the Z score.
You know how many standard
of deviation away.
Suppose in these documents we found
a support vector getting together
is about 12 standard iterations away,
okay?
That means that the support vector
coming together so tight, so
unusual they should be a phrase.
Even you merge support vector as a phrase,
then you still
calculate this machine you find there
are still eight standard deviation away.
Simply says Support Vector Machine
getting together should be a phrase.
The interesting case could
be you see feature selection
some people see selection for
which when should be a good phrase.
Actually if you check
the whole document you'll see
features selection likely
should be a good phrase.
Because they're getting
together is more than expected.
Okay, then you team up with
feature selection as a phrase.
In that case it's selection for
would not be a candidate in this case.
If we do phraser sequestration,
features selection will have a count.
Selection for, in this particular
sentence, will now contribute
to a count to selection for, because
feature selection is already there.
Okay so if we do the good
ratification of the phrase frequency,
we'll be able to make
a very good judgement.
So we did some good
experiments you probably see.
If we use DBLP which is
compromise research publication
bibliographic data base.
We actually can see the unigram
generated and the n-gram generated
has already better quality
than purely topic modelling.
However you see this n-gram
generated very informative.
For example, almost anybody working
on natural language processing,
you probably can see natural language,
speech recognition,
language model, natural language
processing, machine translation.
All these become very,
very good top rank of phrases for
natural language processing.
That implies this phrase mining not only
helps in generating quality phrases but
also generally better
quality topic models.
That means ToPMine is efficient and
generates high-quality topics and
phrases without any training data.
Similar experiments on Yelp.
Yelp actually is a social media data sets.
For Yelp reviews, people writing
something not a quite formerly but still
we probably can see the phrase generated
are actually pretty high quality.
And for example if you look
at this the Mexican food,
the chips and salsa, hot dog, rice and
beans you will see these are the very
typical Mexican food you can generate
using this and phrase mining.
First, do phrase mining,
then do topic mining.
One thing we should note is, for
example, food was good generate here.
Food was good actually is a sentence.
It's a short sentence, it's not a phrase.
If we add a little more, for
example, part-of-speech tagging,
we'll be able to rectify it.
Carried out this food was good as
a short sentence, it's not a phrase.
The remaining ones are pretty good.
So, that implies top mine, and
it can't further integrate
it with some natural language
processing features.
And we will be able to generate
pretty high quality phrases for
the subsequent process.