Now we introduce another interesting
phrase mining algorithm called segPhrase.
This is phrase mining
with tiny training sets.
We have introduced ToPMine.
ToPMining is mining phrases
without any training data.
However if we have a small
set of training data,
it may substantially enhance
the quality of phrase mining.
This was done by Jalo Liu.
He and his collaborators working
on Mining Quality Phrases
from Massive Text Corporate Data, and
they published their work in SIGMOD 2015,
is as follows.
If we have a raw corpus, if we use
a small set of training labels by human.
Of course, later they extended to get
a general knowledge base like Freebase or
Wikipedia.
But in this algorithm we first just study,
suppose we got a small set of
labels by human, like 300 labels.
Then we feed them into a mining process.
We may be able to get a quality phrases
and also get a segmented corpus.
And a quality Phrases and
segmented Corpus can mutually enhance each
other by phrase or segmentation process.
So finally, we'll be able to get
a high quality phrases generated.
So we look at the overall framework.
And the overall framework, the first thing
they introduced comparing
with ToPMine is first to
frequent pattern mining,
feature extraction.
But in the meantime,
they introduce a classification process.
The reason they introduced
the classification process
is because they have the labels.
The label can,
based on the feature extracted,
the classifier will be able to say we can
put more weights on the positive labels.
And then put some negative
labels as a back phrases.
We will be able to work out a classifier.
Okay, that means SegPhrase
itself use a classifier,
okay, and small labeled datasets.
This datasets could be provided by experts
or by a distant supervised knowledge base,
like Wikipedia or DBPedia, okay.
Then If we look at the SegPhrase
is doing phrasal segmentation
and phrase quality estimation.
After that, they will go back and
feed into this classifier again.
To get one more round to
enhance mined quality phrases.
Okay, so that's why they call
this one more round after
phrasal segmentation and phrase quality
estimation, to feed back to the classifier
again as SegPhrase+ process.
Let's look at how they do it.
The first thing they did is doing
pattern mining for candidate sets,
that means using frequent pattern mining
algorithm to get a candidate phrase sets.
That means you mine frequent k-grams.
This essentially is frequent phrases,
but k is typically small,
for example 6 grams.
Of course, for
some other applications that I have,
some medical applications,
k could be even bigger.
The popularity measure is
by raw frequent words and
a phrase mined from the corpus,
this popularity.
Then doing feature extraction
based on the concordance.
That means whether you partition
the phrase into two parts and
check whether the co-occurrence is
significantly higher than the pure random.
Then another feature extraction
process Is informativeness.
That, essentially,
is you assume the quality phrase
typical start end with a non-stopword.
For example, you say,
machine learning is, machine learning.
Likely machine learning is a good phrase.
Machine learning is, this is stop.
Where it starting,
I'm ending with a stop words.
Like this actually is a non-stopword but
is a stopword,
so you basically say, this is,
is not part of the phrase.
Another method or
heuristic is using average IDF.
IDF is inverted document frequency
over the words in the phrase
to measure the semantics.
Simply says if this phrase is
frequent almost in all the documents,
across all the documents in the corpus,
then this IDF is too high.
And it may not be very good at quality.
And if this phrase is, actually, occur
more frequent in some documents but less
frequent in other documents, it becomes
more interesting, more distinctive.
Then another heuristic,
the algorithm users is
considered the probability
of quality phrase in quotes,
brackets, or connected by dash or
hyphen should be higher.
For example,
like state-of-the-art actually is,
it should be a phrase rather than
syncing these several different things.
Then SegPhrase uses
a classification process.
It explores a tiny set of training data.
Usually four gigabytes corpus.
You just need it to have your labels.
But what kind of label it is?
For example, you may say, support
vector machine is high quality phrase.
The experiment shows is not a good phrase.
You just based on the quality of one or
zero.
Then we can construct
a models to distinguish
quality phrases from the poor ones.
And this classifier [COUGH] actually in it
use Random Forest algorithm to boost
different datasets with limited labels.
So you do not using very
small number of labels.
Then you'll miss coverage of the others.
So the Random Forest usually
gives you less bias.
Then phrasal segmentation can tell
which phrase is more appropriate.
For example, you look at this one,
you say a standard feature
vector machine learning setup
is used to describe something.
Actually, instead of thinking this,
like if you say feature vector here,
it's a good phrase.
In this particular one, the vector
machine should be not be combined, but
machine learning should be combined.
So that simply says when you rectify it,
you will not say vector machine
actually got as the real count.
But the feature vector is a good count,
and machine learning is a good count.
Then we can partition a sequence of
the words by maximizing the likelihood.
And consider length penalty.
That means you get too long,
maybe it's not a very good phrase.
Filter out phrases with
low rectified frequency.
Then if the process is a classification,
then do phrasal segmentation.
This part is the SegPhrase the first one.
And for putting plus, actually it's
you feed this phrasal segmentation
process into classification again,
then you do phrasal segmentation again.
This actually derive even better results.
We call this one SegPhrase +.
Now we probably can see
the experimental results.
The data actually used was DBLP and
Yelp was in millions of
documents and tens of millions or
hundreds of millions of words.
But every time, we just used this 300
human label phrases for training.
And then fo r the phrase evaluation,
we use Wiki Phrase and
sampled 500 times 7 Wiki-uncovered
phrases with evaluated by reviewers.
Then you probably can see the readers
comparing with other algorithms.
And you can see comparing to
a few comparative algorithms.
Of course,
it may not be a very fair comparison
if you think TopMine does
not use any training at all.
Well, anyway we put it down
there to give you a relatively
where TopMine is if we do
not use any training data.
So this is a precision recall curve for
DBLP data using Wiki Phrase
as a label to check it.
And the second one is based on DBpedia,
not using Wiki Phrase but
using now Wiki Phrases.
For the Wiki phrases, you probably can
see the difference is pretty high.
Now, Wiki phrases, the phrase read out.
Actually, it's,
you probably can see it's overall,
this method generate a very high
quality comparing to the others.
And also Segphrase algorithm is efficient,
is linearly scalable.
So we look at some real
results people can see.
To my, from the titles and
abstract of ACMCKDD,
the KDD proceedings, you probably can see,
we just need a title and
abstract by using SegPhrase and
comparing with chunking method
using TF-IDF and C value.
And these red ones are phrases
only generated in SegPhrase+ but
not in chunking, these red ones.
And these blue ones, those generated
only in chunking but not in SegPhrase.
But you probably can see in that case,
you'll see like for KDD, time series,
gene expression data, frequent subgraph,
categorical attribute.
These are meaningful good phrases for KDD.
But if you look at a important problem,
effective ways, small sets,
these are the phrases almost
appear anywhere, not just in KDD.
So that means chunking
methods may not generate
as high quality phrases
as like SegPhrase+.
And the interesting thing
is both ToPMine and
SegPhrase+ are extensible to mining
quality phrases in multiple languages.
For example, this is a Chinese
language from the Chinese Wikipedia.
And we probably can see,
these Chinese phrases
are pretty high quality is
generated using SegPhrase.
And it can, my Arabic language,
even without the pre-processing,
you probably can see the results
TopMine can generate those phrases
without any training and pre-processing,
and generate some quality phrases as well.
So in summary, we have studied
pattern mining applications,
mining quality phrases from text data.
We studied why frequent pattern mining
could be useful for phrase mining.
We discussed previous phrase
pattern mining methods.
We introduced two new algorithms.
One is ToPMine, one is SegPhrase.
And this is a set of references,
those published papers,
we have been cited and
compared in our studies.
Thank you.