[SOUND] The first session we're going
to discuss, what is Pattern Discovery.
Why it is important?
To know why pattern
discovery is important,
we need to know what are the patterns.
Okay.
Patterns, actually are a set of
items subsequences or substructures
that occur frequently together in a data
set we call this strongly correlated.
Patterns usually represent intrinsic and
important properties of data.
That's why Pattern Discovery is
the process try to uncover, try to mind
patterns from massive data sets,
it has many interesting applications.
For example, in transaction
database you may want to find
what kind of products
are often purchased together?
Now you can do some target marketing.
And for customers, you may want to
study if a person buying an iPad,
what are likely other products he or
she is going to buy in the future?
And even for software engineering,
you may want,
based on a co second analysis,
to try to find copy-and-paste bugs.
For text analysis,
you may want to see what are likely
the keywords were from phrases, finding
phrases may need pattern mining as well.
We can see Pattern Discovery could
be very important because it
is uncover inherent
regularities in the data sets.
It forms the foundation for many things.
For example, association, correlation, and
causality analysis,
mining sequential structure patterns,
pattern analysis is spatiotemporal data,
multimedia data and stream data.
Even for classification,
ff we use discriminative native
pattern-based analysis,
the classification could be more accurate.
And for cluster analysis,
pattern-based subspace clustering
could be an important direction for
cluster analysis.
So there's no wonder why we want
to study Pattern Discovery.
[MUSIC]