[MUSIC]
We first discussed basic concepts
of density-based clustering.
What is density-based clustering?
Essentially, we do
clustering-based on density.
Which is a local clustering criterion,
that means just to look at surroundings
to see how dense this reading could be.
We may introduce density-connected points.
Its major features are we
can discover clusters
of arbitrary shape rather than just
compact or something like a sphere.
It can handle noise nicely.
You may just use one scan because
it only examines the local
region to justify its density.
But it needs density parameters
as a termination condition.
There are several interesting studies.
For example, DBSCAN,
we are going to cover in this lecture.
Optics, we are going to
cover also in this lecture.
Denclue, we may not have time to cover it,
but it's in the textbook.
CLIQUE, developed by
Rakesh Agrawal's group,
we will cover it in
the grid-based lecture.
[MUSIC]