[SOUND] In this session,
we are going to introduce
a density-based clustering
algorithm called DBSCAN.
DBSCAN is a density-based spatial
clustering algorithm introduced
by Martin Ester,
Hanz-Peter Kriegel's group in KDD 1996.
This paper received
the highest impact paper award
in the conference of KDD of 2014.
This paper developed
an interesting algorithms
that can discover clusters
of arbitrary shape.
Actually, DBSCAN itself is acronym
of density-based spatial clustering
of applications with noise.
The method introduced a new notion
called density-based notion of cluster.
That means a cluster is defined as
a maximal set of density-connected points.
It defines two parameters.
One called Epsom or EPS, it's
the maximum radius of the neighborhood.
That simply says, if you have a point q
using the radius epsom,
supposedly is 1 cm.
You want to find out how many
points include in q's disk.
Then minimum points,
a minimum number of points in
the Epsom neighborhood of a point.
For example, you can define minimum
point as p then this q for sure is
quite dense because it contains
like 11 points within its radius.
Then we can define the Epsom neighborhood
of a point q which is defined as follows.
For any point p is distance
to q if it's decimal equal to Epsom
then this p actually belonged
to this Epsom neighborhood of q.
For example, if you look at this
point you probably can see.
If using this one as q this neighborhood
is including like 5 points so
this one we actually can't
call this one as a call.
But if a does not have
that many neighborhood but
it can be reached by the cluster,
we call is a spotter.
But if it's isolated
cannot form the cluster
cannot be reachable by other clusters,
we call this one outlier or noise.
Now we look at an, a concept
called directly density-reachable.
Directly density-reachable means, for
example, p is directly reachable by q.
The reasoning is p actually is within q's
Epsom neighborhood on the other hand,
q itself is a core point because
q's disk contain a number of points that's
greater than the minimum number of points.
Then we define another notion
called density-reachable.
Density-reachable means
a point p is density-reachable
from a point q with respect
to the radius Epsom and
minimum number of points,
if there is a chain.
There's a transitive closure, okay?
You get the point p1 to pn.
P1 actually is q then you can go to p2,
then p2 is density reachable to p,
eventually.
Then we will say these p, i plus 1 is
directly density reachable from p i and
finally p stands a reachable
from upon a q because there is
a transitive closure of
directly density-reachable.
Then we define another notion
called density-connected.
Then we can say point of p
it's density connected to
point q if there exists a point o,
which is
density-reachable to p and
also density reachable to q.
That means p and q both can be at
the border but as long as there is point
o which can be directly
density-reachable to these two points.
Then these two points
are density-connected or
we say they are in the same cluster.
So we introduce then the DBSCAN algorithm.
The algorithm actually is saying
arbitrarily select upon a p
that means at the very beginning you
can select at any point starting point.
Then you retrieve all the points
density-reachable from p
with respect to Epsom and
the minimum number of points.
That means you try to find from this
p how far it can density-reachable.
That means you first find
directly density-reachable
then find its transitive closure or
the reachable y, okay?
That means you find a core and
then you find the border.
If p is a core point then
the cluster is formed because it
will reach from anywhere,
you'll find you can't reach it.
But if p is a border point, like this one
is a border point, this one is a border
point, then no point at density- reachable
from p for example, like this point, okay?
No point it can't be density-reachable,
then you were think to this one is,
noise [INAUDIBLE].
Then the DBSCAN where the, the,
the next point in the database, it means
you try to find a new point to start.
You will continue this
process until all the points
have been processed so this is the output.
This algorithm is quite efficient
in the sense if you spatial index,
so it accesses neighbors very fast then
the computational complexity of DBSCAN
is O(nlogn),
where n is a number of database objects.
Otherwise, the complexity is O
n square because you have to
check all the points every time but
it comparatively this one is
still pretty efficient algorithm.
However, DBSCAN is sensitive
to the setting of parameters,
this one was published by Karypis
group in 1999 in computer magazine.
They show the DBSCAN, for
example, if you said the minimum
number point is full but
Epsom you said this disc size,
the radius size is 0.5 you actually
find pretty nice clusters.
However, if you said 0.4 you can
see the clusters found many but
they are pretty ugly.
For the same experiments, you could see
for these number of points, if you set
minimum number of points for the Epsom
is 5.0 you find a cross like this.
If principally,
probably even should find two clusters.
On the other hand, if you select point
3.5 you find a bunch of clusters but
they break nice cluster into many.
If you set up upon sweep on zero, you
will find it pretty ugly scenes because
there are many many small scattered
points you found many small clusters.
So we may need to invent another message,
try to fix this one.
That means to make the master less
sensitive to the setting of parameters.
This is the one we're going to
discuss in the next session.
[MUSIC]