[SOUND]
In this session,
we are going to introduce CLIQUE, a
grid-based subspace clustering algorithm.
This algorithm, CLIQUE, actually is
an abbreviation of Clustering In QUEst.
QUEst is an IBM data mining system.
It was developed by a group
of researchers at IBM.
It was published in SIGMOD,
1998 conference.
CLIQUE is a density-based,
grid-based subspace clustering algorithm.
Why it is grid-based?
Because it discretizes the data
space through a grid structure, and
estimates the density by counting
the number of points in a grid cell.
Why it is density-based?
Because a cluster actually is maximal set
of connected dense units in a subspace.
That means a unit is dense
in the fraction of the total
data points contained in the units,
it exceeds certain parameters.
Then you try to connect those dense
units into a structure, into a cluster.
That means it is density-based.
But why it is subspace clustering?
Because it starts from a low dimension,
like a single dimension.
For this particular subspace,
you try to find neighboring dense cells
in arbitrary subspace, and
you can grow into 2-D, 3-D and
find the maximum number of dimensions
in this subspace, it contains clusters.
It also discovers a minimum
description of the clusters.
That means for this particular algorithm,
it automatically identifies
the subspaces of a high
dimensional data space that allow
a better clustering than the original
space using the Apriori principle.
Let's look at an example.
Suppose we want to find
the clusters based on salary,
age and number of vacation weeks.
And we can first start from one dimension,
to find out where are the dense points.
For example, if you just look at salary,
you may find the salary at
the dense points is 20K to 50K.
That part is pretty dense,
especially around 40K.
You find that the age is
pretty dense between 30 to 50,
and is very few, probably, lower ones.
Then, based on number of vacation,
you probably can see the vacation
is clustered around two to four weeks.
That means we find a dense
region in each subspace,
then generate their minimum descriptions.
Then we use this dense region to find
the promising candidates in 2-D space
based on the Apriori principle.
It simply says, if you find
it's dense in 1-D on salary and
on 1-D on h, then you probably can
find that they are combined at one,
that is, you try to find clusters
within this candidate's space.
Similarly, you can find the clusters
within the candidates for
the space in salary and vacation, okay?
Then we can repeat this process
in the level-wise manner in
higher dimensional subspaces
using the Apriori principle.
It simply says, if you find a dense
in this 2-D part and this 2-D part,
then you may find the candidates in this
3-D region based on their intersections.
So the major step of the CLIQUE algorithm
is first try to identify
subspace that contains clusters.
That means we can partition the database
space into the grid structure,
then find the number of points that lie
inside each cell of the grid partition.
Then try to identify the subspaces
that contain the clusters
using the Apriori principle.
That is, we try to identify clusters, and
as a second step determine the dense
units in all subspace of the interests.
Then we determine the connected, dense
units in all the subspaces of interests.
Then, we will generate the minimal
descriptions of the cluster.
That means determine the maximal regions
that cover a cluster of the connected
dense units, then determine
the minimal cover of each cluster.
So this master,
the interesting points is it
automatically finds subspaces of
the highest dimensionality as long
as a high density cluster
exists in those subspaces.
Because if you find a 2-D,
you'll try to find their intersection.
If the 2-D form a cluster,
the intersection is 3-D space,
likely you may be able to find clusters.
It is an insensitive to
the order of records, the input,
and also does not assume
a particular data distribution.
And it scales linearly with
the size of the input, and
has good scalability as the number of
dimensions when the data increases.
But this is a quite efficient algorithm.
The weakness of the method, essentially,
is because we use the grid-based
clustering approach.
So the quality of the results will
depend on how to choose the number and
width of the partitions and
the grid cells.
Nevertheless, it's a very interesting
subspace clustering method.
Finally, I should say all the original
papers on this density-based and
grid-based clustering are listed here.
Also, for Sheryl Aggarwal and
Reddy's book there are two chapters.
One is called Density-Based Clustering
by Martin Ester,
another is called Grid-Based Clustering
by Cheng, Wang and Batista.
They have a very good summary and
also introduce many more methods on
density-based clustering and
grid-based clustering methods.
[MUSIC]