[SOUND] In the first
section we will introduce,
Basic Concepts of Hierarchical Algorithms.
So what is hierarchical clustering?
The hierarchical clustering means we can
start from either singleton cluster,
iteratively merge them into
higher level clusters, okay.
Or we can start from
one big macro cluster,
iteratively split the bigger
cluster into smaller ones.
Then in this way we will
generate a clustering hierarchy,
drawn as a dendrogram like this.
There is no requirement to specify K,
the number of clusters.
And it is more deterministic.
There is no iterative refinement process.
Hierarchical clustering methods
contain two categories of algorithms.
In general, the hierarchical
clustering methods have two
categories of algorithms,
one called agglomerative.
It start with singleton clusters,
continuously merge two
clusters at a time to build
bottom-up hierarchy of clusters.
The second category is
called divisive cluster.
Essentially, it starts
with a huge macro-cluster,
then split them continuous
into two groups.
It will generate a top-down
hierarchy of clusters.
[MUSIC]