[MUSIC]
>> In this session, we're going to examine
agglomerative clustering algorithms.
We already introduced the general
concepts of, you know,
agglomerative and
divideditive clustering algorithms.
Now we look,
from the computer science point of view,
we can think agglomerative clustering
essentially is a bottom up clustering.
That means we start from
the single den clusters,
that means every single element
treated as one cluster.
Then we try to merge
their nearest neighbor
into bigger, bigger clusters and
eventually merge them into one cluster.
This one is a bottom up, or
agglomerative clustering.
In Kaufmann and
Rousseeuw's 1990 book they describe
one algorithm they call AGNES,
or AGglomerative NESting.
This algorithm uses a single-link method,
or we call nearest neighbor method.
And the dissimilarity matrix
try to continuously merge
nodes that have the least dissimilarity,
or the nearest neighbor.
Eventually, all the nodes
merged into one cluster, okay.
That means you start from the singleton,
you try to find its,
everyone's nearest neighbor.
Then you check the, the, the closest
nearest neighbor, you try to merge them.
Okay.
Then once you merge into bigger
cluster you're looking at cluster,
cluster their nearest
neighbor they're single-link.
Then decide which one to merge eventually
you'll merge everything into one cluster.
Actually in the rear agglomerative
clustering algorithms,
they vary different similarity measures.
For example, we just discussed AGNES.
It uses nearest neighbor we
called single-link measure.
You also can use the farthest neighbor,
or diameter.
That's complete link.
Then you can use group average.
That means you average of
everything based on their distance.
Every pair of elements, you average them.
Then you calculate the distance
based on the average link.
Or we can use central link,
that means we look at the distance
between the centroids of those clusters.
Let's examine a little detail
on these different links.
We first look at the single link,
or we call nearest neighbor.
Okay.
So the similarity or
the distance between the two
clusters is defined based
on the most similar or
the closest elements
in these two clusters.
Okay.
Just to give you an example,
suppose one is in U.S., one is in Cuba,
you want to find their closest points.
Likely in the U.S.,
it will be the Key West.
So such kind of merging essentially
is you examine its neighbors,
or the close regions.
So, you know the overall
structure of the cluster.
So, in that context,
you will be able to find irregular shaped,
or non-elliptical shaped,
group of objects.
This link is also sensitive to noise and
outliers.
Because obviously if you get outlier which
is very close to the other one, you may,
you may decide to merge them.
Another approach called complete link is
you check the diameter of the cluster.
The idea is you try to define
the similarity between the two clusters
based on their farthest neighbors.
That means between the most, the
de-similar elements in these two objects.
For example, if you define the distance
between U.S. and Cuba, you probably,
for the complete link, you may pick
up the farthest point in Alaska.
So that's pretty far apart.
So that means you actually try to
merge the two clusters to form
one with the smallest diameter,
because when you merge them together,
you want the final one is pretty compact.
You examine non-local behavior,
you obtain compact shaped clusters.
But this measure also
sensitive to outliers, okay?
Because you probably do not even
want to think about Alaska.
You may think about Hawaii or Guam,
you know, you try to merge them.
That's pretty far apart.
Then we will look at the average link.
The average link between two clusters
actually is rather expensive to compute.
Because what you want to calculate
is the average distance between all
the elements in one cluster and
all the elements in the other cluster.
That means you calculate all
the pairs of the two clusters,
then you try to average them.
For example, if you have a number of
cluster in C sub a is N sub a, and
a number of elements in
cluster C sub b is N sub b.
So what you want to care,
the distance, essentially you will get
total number of pairs is
N sub a times N sub b.
That's pretty big, you know, average time.
So an easy way, or
a more efficient way to calculate
the the distance between two clusters,
actually use centroid link.
The centroid link means you calculate
the centroid of cluster C sub a,
the centroid of cluster C sub b,
then the distance between
the two clusters is defined by
the distance between these two centroids.
And you may even want to put
a weight there for example,
if the cluster C sub a has many,
many points versus
C cluster C sub b,
you want to take this into consideration.
Then we introduce GAAC, or
group averaged agglomerative clustering.
That means,
if you assume the two clusters C sub a and
C sub b be merged into one cluster,
C sub a unit b,
then the centroid will be defined by,
you get a centroid of C sub a.
But you'll time the number
of elements in the cluster,
then you get a centroid of C C sub b
of cluster C sub b, bigger C sub b.
Then the, you want also times
their number of elements.
Then you finally normalize them, okay?
So this is the GAAC measure.
Another interesting Y is people
define one called Ward's criterion.
This Y's centering is to measure
the increase, once you do this merge.
Remember, once you merge the two clusters,
C sub a and
C sub b into C, the sub union b the SSE,
the sum of the squared
distance were increased because
the cluster becomes bigger.
Okay.
Then once it's increased you want
to see the original clustering.
What's the difference?
What's the increase you've got on this?
Okay, this why is defined
using this criteria and
essentially is you look at the distance
between the two centroids and
then you, based on this weight,
you calculate the increase.
[MUSIC]