[SOUND] In this session we
are going to introduce you
an interesting extension of
hierarchical clustering method,
called BIRCH: A Micro-Clustering
Based Approach.
BIRCH is an abbreviation of
Balance Iterative Reducing and
Clustering Using Hierarchies.
It was developed by a group of researchers
in University of Wisconsin in 1996.
The general philosophy is,
it incrementally constructs
a CF tree, or
called a Clustering Feature tree,
which is a hierarchical data structure for
multiphase clustering.
For phase 1, essentially,
it scans the database to construct
an initial in-memory CF tree.
Which is a multi-level
compression of the data that
tries to preserve the inherent
clustering structure of the data.
Then at Phase 2, it uses an arbitrary
clustering algorithm to cluster
the leaf nodes of the CF-tree.
The key idea is multilevel clustering.
The low level it does micro-clustering,
therefore reduces the complexity,
and increases scalability.
At the high level,
it does macro-clustering.
It leaves enough flexibility for
high level clustering using
different clustering methodologies.
The BIRCH methods scales linearly.
That means you, it finds a good
clustering with a single scan, and
then improves the quality
with a few additional scans.
The clustering feature we first
introduce is the CF vector in BIRCH.
The BIRCH Clustering Feature essentially
is suppose you get these five
points into one cluster.
okay?
Then suppose these are the five points,
their positions, okay?
Then the CF vector
contains three components.
One is the number of data points.
The second is a linear sum of
the points in the cluster.
The third one is square
sum of the N points.
Okay.
So you probably can see the,
the first one, 5 means there are 5 points.
The second one acts as a linear
sum of each dimension.
Okay.
The third one actually is
the squared sum of each dimension.
So the Clustering Feature essentially
is the summary of the statistics of
a given sub-cluster, which you can
consider the number is the zeroth,
the first one is the linear,
the second one is the second moments
of the sub-cluster from
the statistic point of view.
That means it will register
the crucial measurements of the, for
computing cluster and
utilizes storage quite efficiently.
So we can look at the,
the general concepts of centroid,
radius, and diameter.
Okay.
The centroid essentially is
the center of the cluster, okay?
Then, suppose we have a vector
of N dimensions, x sub i.
Okay.
Then, the centroid is essentially
computed by the sum of
all the points in this cluster divided
by the number of points in the cluster,
so that what we get is
a centroid of the cluster.
Okay.
Then the radius actually is
the average distance from the member
objects to the centroid.
That essentially is every one you
get a difference with the centroid,
then we use the sum of
their square distance.
Divide by the number of
points in the cluster.
Take their square root.
Essentially it's the square
root of the average distance
from any point of
the cluster to its centroid.
What is diameter?
Diameter essentially is average
pairwise distance within the cluster.
That means if x i and x j is within the
same cluster, so essentially what we want,
we will find is there are total
n times n minus 1 pairs and
we sum up all these pairwise distance
then you get the square root.
That's the diameter.
Then we look at CF Tree
structure in BIRCH.
The CF Tree Structure essentially
is very much like a, B+-tree.
We can do incremental
insertion of the new points.
That means when the new points come,
okay, we can find the closest leaf entry.
Start from the root.
Okay, then we try,
traverse we find the closest entry,
we can add points to the leaf entry and
update the Clustering Feature, CF.
If this entry diameter is greater
than the maximum diameter,
then we'll split the leaf and
if it's possibly we
even will be able to split parents
based on the B+-tree algorithm.
A CF tree has two parameters,
one called branching factor.
That means the maximum number of children.
Another is maximum diameter of
sub-clusters stored at the leaf nodes.
Then a CF tree essentially is
height-balanced tree that stores
the clustering features.
The non-leaf nodes store the sums of
clustering features of their children.
So we can see BIRCH is an interesting
algorithm, because it, it is
an integration of agglomerative clustering
with other flexible clustering methods.
The low level we do micro-clustering.
We explore the CF feature and
BIRCH tree structure.
It preserves the inherent
clustering structure of the data.
At the high level we do macro-clustering.
It provides sufficient flexibility for
integration with other clustering methods.
So this method act, impact to
many other clustering methods and
applications for large data sets.
There are some concerns.
One is the,
the BIRCH tree is still sensitive to
the insertion order of the data points.
Another is,
since the leaf nodes has a fixed size,
the clustering obtained
may not be as natural.
And also, the clusters tend to be
spherical given the radius and
diameter measure as the major parameters.
Still, it is pretty
interesting algorithm and
it can generate quite effective clusters.
[MUSIC]